<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body skill="Skill" user="Dragon Kings" type="charms">
    <charms>
        <name>Piercing The Celestial Veil</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 47</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Opening her Essence to the spiritual plane, the Dragon King using this Step perceives immaterial beings as though they were material. They register to every sense except touch. If the Dragon King's Path rating is greater than an immaterial creature's Essence, it also identifies them as immaterial.
   If an immaterial being with an Essence score greater than the Dragon King's Path rating inhabits a material host, the Dragon King perceives only the spiritual form. For example, if a demonic leech possesses a mortal, then the Dragon King perceives the leech, and not the host, though the two probably communicate as one. The only exception comes through the use of the spirit Charm Ride. If a spirit and a host have formed a complete union with that Charm, then the entity perceived by this power appears to be a graceful amalgam of the two.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch The Celestial Form</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 48</reference>
        <cost>3m or 3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive or Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>Instant or One Scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Piercing The Celestial Veil</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By flooding her chakras with celestial breath, the Dragon King may physically interact with immaterial beings. For three motes, this Step is Reflexive and lasts only for an instant - long enough for a single attack, or to receive a touch-based Charm.
   By activating this Step as a Simple Step and spending an additional Willpower, the Dragon King may interact with immaterial beings for an entire scene. In this case, she may reflexively spend three motes to cancel this Step's effects for a single instant without ending it permanently. She may do so (Path rating) times, and they don't count as Step uses.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Open The Celestial Doorway</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 48</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Touch The Celestial Form</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Surrounding herself with the ringing peals of spiritual bells, the Dragon King may enter a sanctum through its spirit door. She may bring with her a number of individuals no greater than her Path rating, so long as they all stand at the door when she uses the Step. The Dragon King and/or her associates may remain inside the sanctum indefinitely.
   Any spirit with an Essence score equal to or greater than the Dragon King's may attempt to block use of this Step on its sanctum. To attempt to overcome this resistance, the Dragon King reflexively spends a Willpower, and her player rolls a number of dice equal to the character's Path rating. If (her Essence + roll successes) exceeds the spirit's Essence, then the Dragon King and her associates are free to enter.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Summon The Celestial Servant</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 48</reference>
        <cost>10+m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Special (see below)</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Open The Celestial Doorway</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Step is mechanically identical to the Terrestrial Circle spell Summon Elemental (see Exalted, p. 254), except that it does not require a sorcerous ritual to perform. The action to summon the elemental requires one hour of meditation and prayer for each dot of Essence the desired elemental possesses. All of the non-sorcerous dangers (such as retaliation) and limitations (such as time limits) of Summon Elemental apply to the use of this Step.
   Dragon Kings who summon elementals associated with their species's natural elemental affinity may summon an elemental with an Essence score lower than her (Path rating - 1) in mere seconds. In that case, instead of (elemental's Essence) hours, the summoning requires only (elemental's Essence) miscellaneous actions. Dragon Kings who have activated the Step Lithic Understanding (see p. 50-51) can likewise summon weaker earth elementals at the enhanced rate.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Walk The Celestial Road</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 48</reference>
        <cost>Varies</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Summon The Celestial Servant</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By filling herself with radiant celestial light and serenity, the Dragon King may spend (Essence x 5) motes to dematerialize indefinitely. The Dragon King may also dematerialize up to (Essence) willing characters within three yards. Every companion dematerialized with this Charm adds (his Essence) to the mote cost of the Charm. All companions dematerialized with this Charm must remain within three yards of the Dragon King or else they rematerialize. Also, all such companions rematerialize when the Dragon King does but may also rematerialize at will. This Step dematerializes characters once. Its effects end for a character if he or she rematerializes. The Dragon King must be material to dematerialize others. Those under the effect of this Step do not need to eat, drink or breathe while dematerialized.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Bar The Doorway Of The Gods</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Celestial Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of celestial air is the way of the spirit chakra. Its teachings reveal truths of breath and Essence beyond the normal range of existence. By opening herself to the wisdom of spirit, the Dragon King becomes attuned to the elemental will of Gaia and the celestial order of the Unconquered Sun.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to be like and deal with spirits. She learns first to perceive spirits, then to interact with them physically. Further teachings allow the adept to open spiritual doorways. She may eventually learn to draw on her Gaian nature to summon elementals. The master gains the ability to dematerialize herself and others. The Transcendent Dragon of Celestial Air controls the chasm of the material, giving her incredible power over what can be seen and felt and what cannot.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest shaman of the Dragon Kings and the ones most often chosen to be vessels of powerful spirits. Today, the Celestial Air Path is common only amongst the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, though a few nomadic Northern tribes of Pterok have shown an affinity for it.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 48</reference>
        <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene or indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Walk The Celestial Road</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Taking the chasm of the material into the domain of her celestial chorus, the Dragon King controls what may or may not materialize and dematerialize. She may reflexively deny materialization and/or dematerialization to any objects, structures and creatures within a horizontal radius equal to her (Path rating x 10) yards, stretching vertically into infinity. She may also seal off sanctum doors to those she chooses, from either side. Creatures with Essence scores greater than the Dragon King's Path rating may spend one Willpower to defy this Step for a single action. The Dragon King may make broad, sweeping statements about who is affected in what ways, using triggers or passwords of any kind, so long as they are objective. However, she does not automatically detect specific presences. The Step's area of affect moves with the Dragon King.
   Furthermore, spirits who are killed within the area of effect of this Step are treated as though the Dragon King was a god who had slain them (see The Books of Sorcery, Vol. IV - The Roll of Glorious Divinity I, p. 19). She can bind  or slay them permanently.If this Step is used to affect a manse or demesne to which the Dragon King is attuned, it affects any areas of the Dragon King's choosing within the manse's range or the demesne's area of influence.
   If this Charm is activated at the culmination of a 10-minute meditation ritual, the Dragon King creates five immaterial crystals that fly outward on beams of light, forming a pentagonal boundary of immaterial light. These stones hover level to the Dragon King and spin silently, fueling the Step's power. They have no soak and require only a single health level to destroy, but while all five last, so does the Step. This region has 10 times the Charm's normal radius, but it does not move with the Dragon King.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Clarity Of (Sense)</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 49</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <skill>Awareness</skill>
            <name>Keen (Sense) Technique</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Smiling wryly at the unnoticed messages of the world around her, the Dragon King heightens her awareness. When this Charm is purchased, the Dragon King's player chooses sight, hearing and touch, or smell and taste to be heightened. This Step functions as the Solar Charm Keen (Sense) Technique (see Exalted, p. 255-226) for the sense(s) in question. While the Step is active, she may reflexively pay one mote to change the chosen sense(s) this Step covers.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>See The Winds Of Essence</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 49</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <skill>Occult</skill>
            <name>All-Encompassing Sorcerer's Sight</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Clarity Of (Sense)</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Awakening her to the Essence flows around her, this Step bestows all of the effects of the Solar Charm All-Encompassing Sorcerer's Sight (see Exalted, p. 222).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Visions Of Attack And Defense</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 49</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>(Path rating) actions</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>See The Winds Of Essence</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the Dragon King's instincts guide her senses, which guide her mind, add (her Path rating / 2) to the character's Dodge DV. Furthermore, the character is considered to have aimed any ranged weapon that she attacks with, to the maximum extent of her ability. This usually means a +3 internal bonus to attack rolls for ranged attacks, as though the character had taken three Aim actions.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Perception Of Subtle Flaws</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 49</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Visions Of Attack And Defense</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Focusing her predatory instincts, the Dragon King adds her Path rating to the damage of a single attack, and the attack ignores half the soak value of the target's armor. In addition, every subsequent attack supplemented by this Step during the scene benefits from a cumulative +1 bonus to damage. If the total damage bonus from this Step exceeds the target's (Stamina + Essence), then the Dragon King may spend a point of Willpower to make the attack's damage aggravated.
   Furthermore, if the target is an object or structure, double the Dragon King's damage against it.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Ancient Understanding</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 49</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Stackable</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Perception Of Subtle Flaws</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Guided by the light of her third eye, The Dragon King reads the sympathetic connections between things. To use this Step, the Dragon King's player chooses a question related to a person, place or thing. The Dragon King then calmly and lightly touches the target (which may require an attack roll if the target does not wish to be touched). The Dragon King then spends the required cost, and his player rolls (Path rating + Lore). This roll suffers an external penalty as severe as -5 if the question is poorly related to the target, or if the target is badly damaged. Living characters should (at minimum) apply their wound penalty as an external penalty. If the roll is successful, then the Dragon King learns the answer to a relatively simple or harmless question, such as "What is your name?" or "How long ago were you made?" More difficult, complicated, obscure or generally powerful questions require that the Step immediately be successfully reused one to five more times, as determined by the Storyteller. For instance, the Storyteller may decide that psychically probing a deathknight's daiklaive to locate the hidden stronghold of the Deathlord that forged it requires four consecutive uses. Each time the Charm is used increases the depth of the character's knowledge, until she finally realizes the specific details of what she seeks. Most secrets should require no more than four uses. Six uses uncover any secret that has not been quarantined by the Division of Secrets.
   After the first use, the Storyteller tells the player of the Dragon King how many more times she'll have to use this Step, so that the player isn't stuck wasting all of her motes and Willpower on a question that she can't possibly answer. Each consecutive use of this Charm to probe deeper into a target's secrets increases the difficulty by 1, so only strong-willed and wise Dragon Kings possess the ability to discover the most powerful answers to the most difficult questions. Storytellers are urged to take care with this Step and to disallow or penalize frivolous uses on unimportant targets. The power of this Step's revelations can quickly bring an end to a series focused on investigation or secrets.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Inhuman Clarity Of Perception Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Clear Air Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Pterok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of clear air is the way of the third eye. Its teachings reveal the power of stillness and caring. By opening herself to the bittersweet beauty of her own predatory place in nature, the Dragon King sees through the world and reads sutras written in Essence, finding joy and wisdom in the coolness of a snake's scales and the rhythm of the falling rain.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to perceive through the lens of the hunter. She learns first to heighten her senses, then to open her senses to Essence. Further teachings allow the adept to link her perceptions to her predatory instincts. She may eventually learn to find the essential hearts of all things, where weakness waits. The master gains the ability to find answers in the softest currents of secret Essence. The Transcendent Dragon of Clear Air cuts through all deceptions and sees all hidden things.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the greatest hunters of their kind, providing food for their people, defending settlements from their enemies and tracking down criminals. Today, the basic principles of this Path are practiced by most migratory Pteroks, who would never imagine the depths of its noble wisdom.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 50</reference>
        <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <skill>Awareness</skill>
            <name>Eye of the Unconquered Sun</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Ancient Understanding</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Except as noted below, this Step functions identically to the Solar Charm Eye of the Unconquered Sun (see Exalted, p. 226). The primary exceptions involve the Step's cost, type and keywords. Additionally, the Dragon King using it does not have an anima when this Charm is active, and she does not add her Essence in automatic successes to rolls to determine the primacy of this Step's effects.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Lithic Understanding</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 50</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Meditating on the Kata of Lines, the Dragon King achieves communion with the simple properties of earth. She may add her Path rating to all rolls made to understand or work with sand, rock, crystal or other raw mineral substances. This includes stone bricks and worked jewels but not refined metals or the magical materials. This Step also cancels the penalty to Craft rolls suffered by Dragon Kings who lack manual dexterity as long as they are working the pertinent substances. Furthermore, this Step allows characters to work even the hardest stone without any sort of tools, suffering no penalties while doing so. Finally, Dragon Kings with this power active may attune to crystalline artifacts instantly and reflexively, though they must still pay the normal costs to do so.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shape The Earth</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 51</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Lithic Understanding</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Enacting the Kata of Fluid Angles, the Dragon King shapes solid earth like wet clay. When using her claws, she ignores the soak of stone for the Charm's duration and may accomplish in a single scene what would take a craftsman without this Charm a full day. With a miscellaneous action, the Dragon King may alter existing earth to create bridges, handholds or other simple stone shapes. She may also repair (Path rating) health levels to damaged stone objects or structures. Assuming the raw materials are available, she may even create stone wall fortifications (see Exalted, p. 154) at a rate of (Path rating) square yards of fortification per action spent building them, or the equivalent of a martello fortress per scene so spent.
   While using this Charm, an unarmed character may block stone or crystalline weapons without a stunt and receives (Path rating) automatic successes to avoid being disarmed of such weapons.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Empower Crystal</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 51</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Shape The Earth</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Utilizing the Complementary Lattice Completion Method, the Dragon King aids her occult craftsmanship with personal Essence crystal. As long as the Dragon King's Essence remains committed to the task of crystal artifact or manse design or repair, treat the artifact or manse in question as one level lower with regard to the character's efforts.  For instance, crystal artifacts require fewer exotic components and are generally easier to make or repair. Manses become significantly cheaper to construct, and the whole process is greatly sped up. All Ability score requirements remain unchanged. The Dragon King committing the Essence to the project must also be the primary builder and remain on hand during the entire process. Releasing the motes powering this Charm ruins the effort.
       Level-one crystalline manses can be raised by the character alone in a single year. He counts as 100 mortal builders for determining construction time and requires no outside resources. One-dot crystalline artifacts have their creation roll intervals reduced to a day. The creation roll is at difficulty 5. No exotic materials are needed. Combined with the earlier Step Shape the Earth, the Dragon King using this Step can potentially build a simple crystal artifact in one scene or raise a small manse in a week.
   This Step does not assist in the construction of artifacts that require magical materials other than orichalcum or white jade. It can only help produce Earth- and Solar-aspected manses.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Become Stone</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 51</reference>
        <cost>4m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One day</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Empower Crystal</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>While applying the torturous Anglizing Transmutation Principle to himself, the Dragon King's body becomes stone while still yielding to his will. The character gains (Path rating x 2) lethal soak and (Path rating x 4) bashing soak. He also gains Hardness equal to these soak bonuses. The character's unarmed and melee attacks deal additional damage equal to one half the Dragon King's Path rating. He can block lethal damage while unarmed. He also becomes immune to fatigue and exhaustion, need not sleep and can work unceasingly. Until this Charm ends, the Dragon King weighs approximately 100 pounds more (which may cause problems) and can no longer swim, fly or dash.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Command The Earth</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 51</reference>
        <cost>7m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Become Stone</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As a recognized master of the 5,000 Possibilities of Un-changing Things, the Dragon King forces the earth to move with a touch alone. While in contact with the ground, he may reflexively create earth tremors radiating (Path rating x 20) yards, generating an external penalty of -3 to all actions and making dash actions impossible without a stunt or the use of a Charm. Structures in the radius suffer one health level of damage per tick, to a maximum of (Path rating x 20) health levels in one scene. These quakes are not completely under the character's control, and he is not automatically immune to their effects.
   The Dragon King may also command earth and stone to move, repairing structures or creating entirely new ones. He may repair and create structures as though he were using Shape the Earth (see above) and need only touch any part of the structure or the nearby earth. While touching an earth-based structure, the Dragon King may deal to it (Path rating x 4) health levels of damage with a single miscellaneous action if she does nothing else.
   This Step is too slow to be used for attacks, but it can cause massive changes to the area. Over the course of a scene, the Dragon King can wall off an army, build a small castle, dig a new route for a river or just raise a giant obelisk. Though with just a scene this Step can reproduce the work that it would take a team of 100 mortals to accomplish in a day, it cannot create detail or work with extreme precision. Walls are rough and cannot be made with intricate crenellations or arrow slits. Dwellings are structurally functional, but that's all. For these reasons, this Step can't help speed manse construction.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Unity With Earth And Stone</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Solid Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of solid earth is the way of sacred geometry. Its teachings reveal truths of inevitable progress, stoic strength and endurance. By opening himself to the lessons of timeless Ages, the Dragon King becomes as rock, shaping and redefining all stable things.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to shape and affect rock and stone by becoming one with it. He learns first to commune with and easily work stone, even without tools. He then learns to quickly shape rock as though it were clay. Further teachings allow the adept to produce crystalline artifacts and manses. He may eventually learn to become rock himself. The master gains the ability to control and shape large amounts of earth by touch alone. The Transcendent Dragon of the Solid Earth moves effortlessly through earth and shaped stone, fully one with the element.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were the builders of all Dragon King cities. They formed a worldwide guild responsible for the crystal technology and great pyramids that the Dragon Kings are still famous for in the current Age. Today, the secrets of this Path are remembered only by a handful of the Dragon Kings of Yu-Shan, where crystal is out of fashion and such powers are less important. However, many reading crystals can still be found that retain the secret teachings of the Solid Earth Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 51</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Command The Earth</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Having walking to the summit of this Path, stone becomes the Dragon King's plaything. He becomes completely immune to all stone - or earth-based attacks, damage and penalties. He has nothing to fear from stone weapons, caveins or sandstorms. He may pass through the earth as though it were air or water; he could easily walk into a stone wall and swim through it, moving or even sprinting in any direction. This can even allow him to leap out of the ground, launch an attack and duck back into it.
   One clever use of this Step involves launching hand-to-hand attacks from within walls, reaching out to strike nearby opponents. In such a case, the Dragon King is only physically vulnerable if his enemies can break through the wall to hit him. Objects separated from the character while he is deep in the earth become encased until he grabs them again.The perfect unity of this Step even allows the character to see through (Path rating) yards of earth and stone.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Balm Of Health</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 52</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Using ancient methods, the Dragon King empowers him-self or another with supernatural fortification against disease and infection. If the target's player must roll for the target to resist disease or infection during the next day, this Charm will aid him. If the target is mortal, her player may roll to shrug off disease or infection as if the target was an Exalt. If the target is Exalted, or otherwise possesses Exalt-like resistance to disease, then this Charm adds (Path rating) dice to the (Stamina + Resistance) roll to resist infection. This Step affects only the next roll made for the target to resist infection.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Repair</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 52</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Balm Of Health</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Using his highly honed instincts to guide him, the Dragon King's normal repair action restores all an item's health levels. The Dragon King must possess a Path rating equal to the object's Resource value, and his player must succeed on a (Intelligence + Craft) roll at the difficulty normally necessary to craft the object. If he lacks the Path rating or fails, then the item still looks like it will function, though it will break the first time it is dramatically appropriate. This Step does not repair damage from normal wear or time. It will not heal damage caused by missed maintenance. It cannot replace parts that are missing. This Charm cannot repair objects made or enhanced by Essence, artifacts or objects made of the magical materials.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Speed Healing</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 52</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Repair</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King's soft assurances and firm touch speeds the target's natural healing. While this Step's Essence is committed, the target heals bashing and lethal damage at (Path rating) times his normal speed.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Restore</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 52</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant or one day</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Speed Healing</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By asking the spirit of an object about its history and delving into its creation, the Dragon King is able to turn back the clock while making repairs. The supplemented repair action automatically repairs all damage and returns any mundane object to its prime, even if pieces of the object are missing. If repairs would not normally require significant Resources to perform, then the duration is instant. Otherwise, the duration is one day, and the Step ends if the Dragon King ventures more than 100 yards from the object. He may only restore mundane objects with this Step, not artifacts.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Empower Healing</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 52</reference>
        <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One week</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Restore</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By supplementing a healing action with a course of treatment involving leaps of logic and unfathomable methodologies, the Dragon King may heal nearly any infirmity or injury and reinforce the target against further harm. Whenever the target suffers damage or experiences a Crippling, Poison or Sickness effect (including those already present), the Dragon King's player rolls a number of dice equal to his character's (Intelligence + Medicine), at a difficulty determined by the potency of the effect. Crippling, Poison and Sickness effects range from difficulty 1 to difficulty 5 (or occasionally higher). A Poison's difficulty is equal to its Toxicity. A Sickness's difficulty is equal to its Untreated Morbidity if it is untreated, or Treated Morbidity if it is successfully treated. A Crippling effect's difficulty is determined by its severity, as determined by the Storyteller, but generally ranging from 1 to 5. Only very powerful supernatural Crippling effects should exceed difficulty 5. Healing these effects requires a number of days equal to their difficulty, during which time the character's condition does not worsen. If the roll is instead successfully made to heal wounds, then the target heals from them extremely quickly. Bashing damage is difficulty 1, and all a character's bashing health levels can be completely healed in one tick. Lethal damage is difficulty 2, and it heals at one health level per action. Aggravated damage is difficulty 5, and it heals at one health level per scene.
   The character cannot heal conditions or damage with a difficulty greater than her Path rating. If the Dragon King's player botches one of this Step's Medicine rolls, if its duration ends or if she withdraws her Essence, all healing ends, and negative conditions resume their normal course. Any effects that remain when the Step's effect ends cannot be healed by the same Dragon King with this Step until her Medicine score or Path rating increases.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Regain The Glory Of The Past</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Yielding Earth Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of yielding earth is the way of abstracted methodologies. Its teachings reveal the power of remembrance, love and gratitude. By opening himself to the desire to help and make things whole, the Dragon King finds fulfillment in the working of miracles and the glory of answered prayers.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to repair things and restore the injured to health. He learns first to protect people from disease, then to mend broken objects. Further teachings allow the adept to speed natural healing. He may eventually learn to turn back the damaging effects of time. The master gains the ability to heal almost any disease, condition or damage suffered by himself or others. The Transcendent Dragon of Yielding Earth can fix and completely renew absolutely anything, if he is willing to pay the price.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were public ser-vants -often members of powerful theocracies but occasionally free agents plying their skills where they felt the most needed. Today, the Yielding Earth Path has been all but wiped out by the Division of Endings, who deemed that its most powerful techniques were dangerous to the established order. Those few Dragon Kings vowing to retain its secrets have fled to hidden places and use their powers with extreme caution.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 53</reference>
        <cost>25m, 2wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Empower Healing</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>or indefiniteUsing the ideal of an object as his template, the character may repair almost anything, restoring it to the beautiful way that it once was. The Dragon King must possess at least a tiny part of something that has been in better shape. It must be a basically physical, single thing, that is not made up of multiple sophisticated things, but anything is possible within those limitations.
   The repair requires a full scene of dedicated concentration while nobody else observes or interferes. At the end of the scene, the target is repaired, despite all logic. All parts that the Dragon King did not possess to incorporate into the repairs vanish (or become henceforth unrelated to the target). All that remains is to explain to the pattern spiders exactly how it was done.If regular old repairs could've done the job, then the explanation is simple enough. Reality waves its hand. If the target requires prerequisites to repair or rebuild that the Dragon King could not possibly possess, or if time itself was rewound, then reality calls for an explanation.
   In that case, the Dragon King must continue to commit the Essence powering the Step while embarking on a spiritual quest determined by the Storyteller. The quest should overlap with the current story to avoid removing the character from the series. If the character maintains her commitment and completes the quest, then all is well. Otherwise, the target is once again broken, and he may not attempt another repair unless his Essence (somehow) increases.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>First Light</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 53</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King lights the way. She causes any part of herself or a touched object to glow, brightly illuminating the area around for 10 yards. In very brightly lit areas, a character carrying the target around unconcealed suffers a -2 external penalty to Stealth rolls to hide. In dark areas, such an un-concealed object makes normal stealth impossible.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Lesser Conjuration Of Flame</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 53</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>First Light</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King's fury boils up through her flesh and covers a part of herself or a touched target in a medium-sized heart's flame (see "Playing with Fire", p. 55). If the Dragon King ignites her natural weapons, the damage from the flames is not applied separately but added directly to her normal damage. In that case, it also is considered a part of her and cannot be controlled by any outside force.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Bolt Of Fire</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 53</reference>
        <cost>1m per 2L</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Lesser Conjuration Of Flame</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King passionately discharges her rage and casts it off as a spear of golden flame. Use her (Dexterity + Thrown) to target the bolt, which has an accuracy bonus equal to her Path rating. The bolt has a maximum range equal to (Path rating x 20) yards and suffers no accuracy penalties out to that range. Damage from the attack equals 2L per mote spent creating the flame, plus attack successes. No more than (Path rating) motes may be spent in this way.
   By spending an additional three motes when using this Step, the attack creates a medium-sized heart's flame (see "Playing with Fire", opposite) where it strikes, which burns for (Path rating) actions unless extinguished.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Command Fire</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 54</reference>
        <cost>4m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Bolt Of Fire</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King's burning heart communes with the fire, allowing her to direct and control it. The character chooses a source of fire no larger than a bonfire or a section of a larger fire of equivalent size within (Path rating x 20) yards. She becomes immune to harm from that fire and may use one miscellaneous action during each of her actions to direct the flame in one of the following ways:
• She may cause the flame to change size by one category or extinguish a small fire.
• She may direct the flame not to harm anything that it otherwise would. It will obey her until she directs otherwise.
• She may cause the flame to move as far as (Path rating x 2) yards per tick. Characters in the path of this flame may attempt to dodge out of its way if there is room to do so. This requires a reflexive (Dexterity + Dodge) roll at a difficulty 1 for a small flame, difficulty 2 for a medium flame or difficulty 3 for a large flame. Characters who fail this roll suffer damage from the fire.
• She may the direct the fire to attack a single target near or within the fire. The range of this attack is one yard for a small flame, three yards for a medium flame or 10 yards for a large flame. The character uses (Wits + Path rating) to target the attack, which is subject to multiple action penalties. Medium fires have an accuracy bonus of +1. Large fires have an accuracy bonus of +3. If the target of the attack is already being burned by the fire, then the attack cannot be dodged or blocked. Successes from the attack add to this damage, but armor applies to it as well.
   Command Fire can be used to control heart's flame (see "Playing with Fire", opposite), which acts like a normal fire while controlled. If the fire is extinguished, then this Step ends. The character may control as many as (Path rating) fires at once through repeated use of this Step and may use a miscellaneous action on each when she acts. Only one commanded fire may actually occupy the space of a particular target at once, but all fires within range can issue attacks.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Immolation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 54</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Command Fire</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Releasing the purest fire within, the Dragon King projects an orb of golden devotion, which explodes into a large heart's flame (see "Playing with Fire", opposite) upon impact that burns for (Path rating x 3) actions. The attack uses the same system as Bolt of Fire above, except that it cannot be parried and can only be dodged by targets that have the space to escape the area of effect.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch Of Blazing Fire</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Blazing Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of blazing fire is the way of trial by fire. Its teachings reveal the glory of idealistic devotion and unmitigated passion. By opening and devoting herself to the arduous road of righteousness and purity, the Dragon King burns away weakness and doubt as she burns away her enemies.The Steps of this Path allow the Dragon King to create and control fire. She first learns to generate light, then Essence-fueled fire. Further teachings allow the adept to project bolts of fire. She may eventually learn to command even large fires with her will alone. The master gains the ability to project enormous Essence-fueled bonfires that can quickly ignite her enemies. The Transcendent Dragon of Blazing Fire can instantly start great mystical fires anywhere that she can touch.During the First Age, walkers of this Path were warriors and priests. Every fire was an observance of their valiant sacrifices. Today, the Blazing Fire Path in Yu-Shan has been reduced to a set of esoteric devotions. In Creation, it has become nothing more than strange lights occasionally emitted by angry Anklok.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 55</reference>
        <cost>7m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Immolation</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>One with the single-minded purity of flame, the Dragon King becomes immune to fire's effects (even those of magical fires) and can reflexively set ablaze anything she touches. A fire thus created is heart's flame (see "Playing with Fire", above). It can be small, medium or large. Regardless of its size, it can be made to burn with heat as soft as a candle's touch or as destructive as a bonfire's wrath.
   Furthermore, while this Step is in effect, any heart's flame created by the Dragon King is invested with her righteousness. It will not burn anyone who shares with her an Intimacy based on pure love (for a common other, not for each other). Nor will it burn things that were deliberately built to be used in service of such an Intimacy. It deals aggravated damage to anyone toward whom the Dragon King possesses an Intimacy based on hatred or anger, as well as creatures of darkness. Philosophical or religious Intimacies overrule mundane ones when there is a conflict. Motivations are treated like Intimacies and overrule them as well.
   Finally, by spending a point of Willpower when creating a heart's flame, the character may cause it to remain as such forever. Only after its target has burned away will the fire die out naturally. Such fires may exist for centuries or longer on stone floors, providing free light and heat, or perpetually powering machines. These fires carry the righteousness of ancient priests and are used for ritual tests of purity by some peoples.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Flashing Agility</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King trades standing for reacting, her player adding the character's Path rating to all Athletics and Join Battle rolls.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Fiery Prowess</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Flashing Agility</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King trades failure for boldness, her player adding the Dragon King's Path rating to a single Dexterity roll. A static value derived from the character's Dexterity may be increased by (Path rating / 2) instead.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>One Fire, Many Flames</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>3m per additional action</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Extra Action</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Fiery Prowess</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Trading a thoughtful second for a flashing moment, the Dragon King may construct a magical flurry involving up to (Path rating - 1) physical actions.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Speed Of Flame</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>One Fire, Many Flames</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Trading what's behind for what's ahead, the Dragon King travels with the blessings of movement's potential. She adds (Path rating x 2) to her Strength and Dexterity with regard to her jumping distances and movement speeds. Furthermore, the character may navigate obstacles or cross difficult terrain, water, airspace, etc. at full speed. Also, the character is so nimble and light that water and similarly fluid liquids are no impediment and can even be useful surfaces. She may run across a still lake, soar through a rainstorm (with wings) or swim up a waterfall. Finally, whenever the Dragon King successfully dodges a melee attack that is part of a flurry, her movements can nullify any remaining attacks against her. If her Path rating is greater than the attacker's Dexterity, such attacks are lost. Reach weapons (or similarly long range melee attacks) are immune to this effect.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Twice-Flickering Flame</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Speed Of Flame</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Trading anticipation for effectiveness, the final physical action of any natural or magical flurry the Dragon King performs does not count toward his DV penalty or multiple action penalties. The action itself suffers no multiple action penalties.
   For example: A Dragon King using this Step decides to launch a flurry involving three attacks. The first attack suffers a -2 penalty, and the second suffers a -3 penalty, as though the character were only making two attacks. Finally, her third attack uses her full dice pool. She suffers a -2 penalty to her DV, as though she had launched two attacks. Without this Charm, the Dragon King would have suffered -3, -4 and -5 to her attacks. She would then have to deal with a -3 DV penalty.
   The "free action" from this Step can be added, without Essence cost, to the end of any magical flurry, as long as the "free action" would have been a valid action in the flurry. It can even lengthen a magical flurry that already contains the maximum number of actions.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Perfection Of Movement</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flickering Fire Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Anklok
   Associated Virtue: Valor
   The way of flickering fire is the way of pilgrimage. Its teachings reveal the power of courage and action. By opening herself to change and subduing her fear, the Dragon King takes control of her own destiny and becomes a true hero.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control her movements. She first learns to react quickly and athletically, then to perform brilliant maneuvers of true dexterity. Further teachings allow the adept to perform simultaneous actions without dividing her concentration. She may eventually learn to perform impossible feats of acrobatics with the speed of a flashing fire. The master gains the ability to save up her kinetic powers for just the right moment in order to unleash furious techniques from the middle of a whirlwind of motion. The Transcendent Dragon of Flickering Fire can move with total confidence, dodging all attacks and evading all obstacles.
   During the First Age, knowledge of this Path was quite common. Because the Path's tenets were so useful and comforting to developing Dragon Kings, Anklok missionaries carried its lessons to all corners of Creation. However, incidents of recklessness blamed on the Path and a growing loathing for reckless heroism eventually led to a drastic decline in the Flickering Flame Path in non-Anklok territories. It was seen as self-aggrandizing and hubristic and became the domain of criminals and duelists. Today, many developing Dragon Kings seek out the wisdom of this Path for self-defense but come to find that it leads them into danger.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 56</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Twice-Flickering Flame</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Fully trading possibility for movement, the Dragon King suffers no penalties to her DVs from the actions that she performs, from onslaught or from coordinated attacks. She also suffers no penalties at all resulting from positioning, such as penalties from lack of leverage or cover. She suffers no penalties related to balance and need take no actions nor concern herself at all with unstable footing. She may swim and climb at her full dash speed and may take any movement-based action reflexively. So long as the character can fit her head through a space, she can maneuver at full speed through it without suffering the slightest penalty while doing so. The character cannot be grappled or bound. Though she must still use normal movement methods to get around (no flying without wings, etc), she can move at full speed through any opening large enough to accommodate her head. Basically, only walls stop her or even slow her down.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Clinging Puddle Style</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 57</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>It's easy for the Dragon King to remain where she is. The Dragon King can walk across solid surfaces regardless of angle, so long as a surface can support her weight, and her player adds (Path rating) successes to rolls for the character to resist knockdown and knockback. The wall-walking effect is temporarily disabled if the Dragon King attempts a dash action, which requires more speed than the Step allows.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Air Walking Style</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 57</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>Until next action</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Clinging Puddle Style</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>After thinking about it for a while, the Dragon King can walk on substances too weak to support her weight, such as paper, water, smoke, clouds or even air. Her move action can take her up, down, diagonally or in any other unoccupied direction. The character may reorient herself sideways in relation to the ground, upside down or any other way she chooses. She can turn air corners and generally do in three dimensions anything that she could with a move action on land. As the character's DV refreshes, she must reactivate the Step to stay afloat. Without it, the character descends, ignoring the first 10 yards of space when determining falling damage.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Vault-Breeching Method</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 57</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Air Walking Style</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the world bends before her piercing logic, the Dragon King may penetrate any barrier not made of the magical materials. She can't go all of the way through, but she can push any extremity through, so long as at least half of her body remains on the original side. The character's body doesn't magically lengthen or half-teleport, so she can only reach through to the other side of a barrier if it's thin enough. This Step lasts until the end of the scene or until the Dragon King completely returns to the original side.
   This Step does not help the Dragon King to see through opaque solids, but she can simply push her head through a wall to see to the other side. Easily carried objects that the character possesses travel with her as she passes through, so she could grab into a locked chest to steal its contents. This property can be manipulated to allow the character to deposit small possessions within solid objects. The Dragon King may even launch attacks on the other side of a barrier from 75% cover (or 100% if she doesn't need to see), but she suffers a -1 external penalty to combat rolls from awkward positioning and cannot use her Dodge DV unless she returns to the other side of the wall (and thus ends the Step).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Barrier Breaching Method</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 57</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Vault-Breeching Method</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As reality finally succumbs to her mystical reasoning, the Dragon King may move completely through any barrier not constructed of the magical materials. She simply pushes against the barrier and walks through. However, the character may not move further through solid material than she could travel with a Move action in a single tick, nor may she pass through more than (her Path rating) yards of solid material. This Step can be used while Vault-Bypassing Method is in effect, so the character may look before she leaps.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Distance Ignoring Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 57</reference>
        <cost>6m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Barrier Breaching Method</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Through proven division by zero, the Dragon King fades from existence and ripples into being at a destination up to (Path rating x 30) yards away. If she can clearly see where she is going, the effect works automatically. If she can't, she'll still go somewhere but not exactly where she wants. The Dragon King's player rolls (Intelligence + Path rating), difficulty 1. This roll suffers cumulative -1 external penalties if the target is extremely small, busy, cramped, unfamiliar, unlike she expects, a misestimated distance away or in a misestimated direction. The Dragon King may bring along up to (Essence x 50) pounds of material along for the ride.
   On a successful roll, the character appears where she wants to be. On a failure, the character ends up somewhere nearby and cannot use this Step again until she can figure out where she is in relation to her origin or her destination. On a botch, the character finds herself in a bad spot, teleporting high into the sky, in front of an oncoming danger or even into a solid object. The exact results are up to the Storyteller, but being shunted from a solid object causes at least 10 dice of aggravated damage, which bypasses armor. No matter what, a character who botches cannot use this Step again for the remainder of the scene.
   To use this Step, the character must know where she is and must know the location of where she is going fairly well. She cannot find places if she has no idea where they are, though she can get to places even if she's a little off target.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Create Gateway</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Flowing Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of flowing water is the way of mathematical numerology. Its teachings reveal the power of detached contemplation and creative analysis. By opening herself to the true facts of Creation on a grand scale, the Dragon King learns to bypass the most daunting "limitations".
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to manipulate her location. She first learns to hold onto wherever she is, then to move in impossible directions. Further teachings allow the adept to reach through solid barriers. She may eventually learn to step completely through such barriers. The master gains the ability to actually teleport, even to places that she cannot see. The Transcendent Dragon of Flowing Water can open portals connecting distant places that others may travel through.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were merchants, criminals and politicians. Many of the most prominent and wealthy Dragon Kings throughout the Age were advocates of the Path of Flowing Water. Today, even the initial lessons of this Path are lost on most Dragon Kings. A few animalistic Mosok have picked up the basic lessons, but only ambition triggers the true power of this Path.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 58</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>(Path rating) actions</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Distance Ignoring Technique</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Exploiting an array of Creation's inconsistencies that are nevertheless true, the Dragon King creates a semi-permanent gateway between two distant points in space. The gateway appears as a shimmering oval disk of solid light between one and six yards in diameter. Anyone (not anything) from either side who touches the portal, willingly or not, is instantly transported to the other side. The portal lasts for (Path rating) actions or until she wills the portal to close.
   One end of the gateway appears before the Dragon King. Targeting the other end uses exactly the same system as Distance Ignoring Technique above, with necessary rolls being made in secret. As a result, an overzealous Dragon King can very possibly send six of his good friends to their doom. Successful gateways cannot connect different realms of existence, such as Creation and Yu-Shan, but botched rolls can create gateways to very bad places. Sometimes, the very bad things that live in those places can come through. Caution is advised.
   If the Dragon King uses this step to or from a manse or demesne to which she is attuned, or if she activates the Charm at the culmination of a 10-minute preparatory ritual, then the maximum range of the gateway is extended to (Path rating) miles.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Averting The Eyes</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Cloaking herself in fabricated normalcy, the Dragon King achieves an effect identical to the Solar Charm Easily Overlooked Presence Method (see Exalted, p. 230).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Visage Of The New Face</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One day</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Averting The Eyes</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Lacing her Essence with wild stereotypes and subtle fears, the Dragon King assumes the guise of any reptilian creature with two arms and two legs that is no more than 50% larger or smaller than herself. She appears as a non-specific member of the species, but she may also attempt her own disguise to impersonate specific members of her new apparent species. This guise is not an illusion, but it does not provide any of the powers or mechanical benefits of the new form. It works as an instant disguise that automatically scores a threshold equal to the character's (Path rating + 5).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Guise Of The New Form</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One day</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Visage Of The New Face</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>With a cunning application of insanity, the Dragon King affects a guise in a manner much like with Visage of the New Face, except that she may become any humanoid creature no more than 50% larger or smaller than herself.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Unseen Form Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>4m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Guise Of The New Form</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Artfully distracting the Essence of observation, the Dragon King becomes invisible. The results of his actions (opening doors, tracks, etc) are still visible, but he is not. Anyone attempting to notice or target the character suffers an external penalty of -2. If the Dragon King stands still, the external penalty to find him worsens to -4. Unless the Dragon King deliberately makes his location known, it always requires a roll to find him. This roll usually benefits from a bonus of +1 to +3 if onlookers know that he couldn't have gotten far since they last noticed him.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Veil Of Deception</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>6m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Unseen Form Technique</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>With impossibility in hand and insanity on her tongue, the Dragon King may instantly disguise any person or object as virtually any other person or object no smaller than a cat nor larger than a moose. This Charm does not disguise the nature of the target's actions and does not actually change her size or shape. It is an illusion. Observers whose MDV is greater than the Dragon King's Path rating may spend four Willpower to see the target for what she truly is. This is reduced to one Willpower if the target acts out of character. If the Dragon King attempts to create an exact appearance by memory, then he must make a disguise roll, but the final difficulty is always 1. The Dragon King may use this Step on himself.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Perfection Of Illusion</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shimmering Water Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Mosok
   Associated Virtue: Conviction
   The way of Shimmering Water is the way of riddles and hallucination. Its teachings reveal the power of assumptions and perspective. By opening himself to the lessons of belief and denial, the Dragon King learns to forge a new reality of misdirected perceptions.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to disguise and obscure. He first learns to go unnoticed, then to become something other than what he is. Further teachings allow the adept to drastically alter his appearance. He may eventually learn to turn completely invisible. The master gains the ability to precisely and radically disguise almost anyone or anything. The Transcendent Dragon of Shimmering Water can precisely and powerfully influence the perceptions of everyone nearby in almost any way.
   During the First Age, this Path was feared and shunned. Teaching it was usually forbidden, and private tutelage was generally done in secret. However, the Path's usefulness was undeniable. Criminals, guilds and governments alike made secret use of specially trained shimmering water operatives. Today, the Shimmering Water Path is invaluable to Dragon Kings who wish to travel through human areas without drawing attention. Some Mosok in the West have opened themselves to its secrets, and a few enlightened ones can be found (with difficulty) traveling in less organized cities there.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 59</reference>
        <cost>7m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <duration>(Path rating) actions</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Veil Of Deception</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By stunning reality and taking over where it left off, the Dragon King manipulates what everyone perceives about the area around her for 100 yards. Everyone perceiving into that radius from outside it is subject to her uniform, though potentially dramatic description of it but is otherwise safe. Anyone within whose MDV is lower than the Dragon King's Path rating can be made to truly experience the full magnitude of her whims. She can determine who perceives what, and to what extent. She can make them see/feel/etc just about anything. At the extreme, this can make virtually any actions impossible and can easily cause severe longterm mental damage or addiction. To those whose MDV is not lower than the Dragon King's Path rating, the scene cannot be made so dramatically different as to cause more of an internal penalty than the Dragon King's Path rating and an external penalty of half that. Four Willpower can be spent to pierce the illusions. If the illusions are pointed out as such or seem impossible, or if a successful roll of (Perception + Awareness) is made at a difficulty equal to the Dragon King's Path rating, then the cost to pierce the illusions drops to one Willpower.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Verdant Understanding</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 60</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Opening his heart to the whispered green pulse of life, the Dragon King feels plants in powerful ways. This Step is identical to the Charm Lithic Understanding (see p. 50-51), except that it helps with plant-based materials and artifacts, not earth.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Empower Cultivation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 60</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Verdant Understanding</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Saturating a plant with an adoring stream of Essence, the Dragon King causes it to successfully grow despite extremely poor conditions. The plant requires much less sunlight, water and other nutrients and can grow in cramped places and awkward positions. With this Step, pine trees can be grown in the desert, and small trees will flourish in the darkest jungle. Plants that would normally require the Wyld to survive can also be reinforced with this Step to grow in Creation.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Empower Plants</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 60</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Empower Cultivation</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Sharing a heartfelt conversation with their least gods, the Dragon King encourages the growth of occult plant life. This Step functions identically to Empower Crystal (see p. 51), except that it benefits working with Wood-aspected manses of a rating no higher than one half the character's Path Rating and plant-based artifacts that require none of the magical materials besides green jade.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shape Plants</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 60</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basis</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Empower Plants</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Singing idly, mixing the songs of the red with those of the green, the Dragon King may cause any plants that he is touching to reshape themselves. Trees bend, grasses tie knots, and vines can snake up free from support. This Step instinctively helps the character to move rapidly through wooded areas and to cover his tracks. In appropriate situations, it automatically grants a one-die bonus to rolls that can be assisted by mobile plants. In areas of dense plant life, this bonus increases to the character's Path rating for physical rolls.
   By focusing his song, the Dragon King can speed mundane construction that requires only plant-based parts. With a single miscellaneous action, he can permanently create excellent mundane small wooden objects, so long as his Craft (Wood) score would be sufficient to do so normally. On larger or more complex projects, he can accomplish in a scene what would otherwise require a day. These constructs can be made as living parts of the plant, or new living plants themselves. This Step does not shape dead plant material, but objects can be grown to be easy to break free of the original plant. Plants with sentience or an Essence score are immune this Charm's effects.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Alter Plants</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 60</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Shape Plants</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As he embraces the teachings of Primordial Gaia, the character empowers all plants he touches with his living Essence. The Dragon King may instantly and perfectly communicate with the spirits of all plants he touches and may even read their minds and memories, so long as their Essence does not equal or exceed his own. The Dragon King may reflexively induce rapid growth or healing in all non-magical plants, causing approximately a year's worth of growth over a single scene and healing one health level per tick. By focusing, the character may use a full scene of contact to alter the biological properties of any plant, mak-ing it as poisonous, resilient, fast-growing, etc as any plant with which he is familiar, or more so. These new plants are designed as artifacts and require all of the Abilities that designing artifacts requires, but no resources or exotic components are needed. All work is done in one scene, within the plant. A single (Intelligence + Craft [Wood]) roll is made, with a difficulty equal to double the artifact plant's rating. Failure kills the plant. A botch creates a flawed plant and affects the plant's spirit in unpredictable ways. Artifact plants still require the things that plants require and usually need more maintenance and are much more susceptible to damage than metal or stone artifacts. Also, they will eventually die.
   The character may also spend three motes and a miscellaneous action to empower the governing spirit of a touched plant with an Inhabiting Charm that allows it to physically control and move the plant. Optionally, this effect can force the spirit to do so and to obey the character's verbal commands (and mental commands for as long as he touches the plant). The plant's Physical Attributes are equal to one half the character's Path rating. The plant's Abilities are limited to the spirit's Abilities, which are usually 0 in the case of least gods. Major trees may have much more powerful spirits. All plants suffer bonuses and/or internal penalties ranging from -5 to +5 to rolls that are appropriate to the type and size of the plant involved. Vines make good clinchers, for instance, but small shrubberies don't. Normal plants typically have object soak values ranging from 0 to 6 and health levels determined by size. A huge redwood could have hundreds and hundreds of health levels. A blade of grass would have only one. A young tree might have five to ten. Plants typically do bashing damage, but large trees can do lethal damage. Plant animation ceases when this Step ends. Plants with an artifact value greater than one half the character's Path rating are likely to be too powerful for their spirits to animate, though some powerful spirits could potentially manage it.
   No plant may benefit from this Step more than once in a month. Any attempt to use this Step again within that time kills the plant. Plants with an Essence score are unaf-fected by this Step.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Plant Walk</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Growing Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Compassion
   The way of growing wood is the way of living auras and vibrations. Its teachings reveal the simple beauty of life. By opening himself to the joy of living, growing and loving Creation, the Dragon King finds bliss and brilliance in the beauty of a single leaf.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to control and empower plants and communicate with their spirits. He first learns to understand and precisely cultivate plants, then to strengthen and protect them. Further teachings allow the adept to cultivate magical plants and even Wood-aspected manses. He may eventually learn to rapidly use plants to his advantage in a variety of ways. The master gains the ability to drastically alter plants in very powerful ways and to empower their spirits to animate them. The Transcendent Master of Growing Wood can become one with plants in body and spirit, moving through them and replenishing himself with their vitality.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were artists and scientists. Though they were occasionally skilled craftsmen, practitioners of the Shaping Earth Path and their constructions were more reliable. This Path was usually no more than a liberal road to self-fulfillment, but some advanced and unappreciated Dragon Kings saw in it vast scientific potential. Today, Raptok who manage to make decent existences for themselves occasionally awaken to the Path's basic lessons, and more advanced Dragon Kings in Rathess utilize it toward destructive ends. The Growing Wood Path has always been rare outside of the East.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 61</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Alter Plants</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Synchronizing himself fully with the songs of the green, the Dragon King walks in the auras of the wood. This Step is identical to the Charm Unity with Earth and Stone (see p. 51-52), except that it allows freedom within living and dead plant material. In addition, while the Step is active, the character may (and must) interact physically with all plant spirits and wood elementals. Also, as long as the character is within living plant life, he regains one mote of Essence each tick. If the character uses this Step in conjunction with the animating force of Alter Plants above, then he may substitute his own Ability scores for those of the animating spirit for the purposes of controlling a plant that he is contained within.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shaping The Bark</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 61</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Drawing on the primal wisdom of her ancestors, the character toughens and sharpens her physical form at the expense of grace. When this Step is activated, the Dragon King decides at what level she wishes to activate it. The maximum level she can attain is equal to the character's Path rating. Benefits of escalating levels are cumulative.
   Activating this Step or increasing the Step's level requires but a moment, but deactivating the Step or reducing its level requires one scene for each level that the Step's effect is taken down. Health levels gained by this Charm are not automatically healed if the Step is deactivated.
    Level Effect
    1 +1B/+1L soak, -1 Appearance (min 0)
    2 +1 damage with natural weapons, -1 external penalty to Dexterity
    3 +1B/+1L soak, +1 damage with natural weapons, -1 Appearance (min 0)
    4 +1B/+1L soak, +1 damage with natural weapons, no armor or weapons
    5 +1 Stamina, +1 (-2) health level, -1 Charisma (min 0)
    6 +1 Strength, +1 (-1) health level, no speech</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Alter The Trunk</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 61</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 8, -2 DV)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Shaping The Bark</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Assuming the undername of the Legendary Champion, the character enhances her size and flexibility. She gains 50% additional height and reach but may squeeze through cracks no less than four inches wide. Furthermore, this adjustment adds one to Strength and Dexterity. Common Undernames: Atlaaki, Caltia, Octavian.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Adaptation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 62</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One day</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Alter The Trunk</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Assuming the scars and intername of the Unalterable Guardian, the Dragon King adds one half her Path rating to her Stamina. Also, her player adds the character's Path rating as successes to all rolls to resist environmental hazards. Common Internames: Leviathan, Mostath, Cecelyne.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Form Of Another Breed</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 62</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Adaptation</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Assuming the surname of a Dragon King breed, the character becomes a member of that breed. For instance, a Pterok could use this Step to become a Mosok, losing the ability to fly, Dexterity and Perception, but gaining Strength, Stamina and excellent swimming ability. Natural attacks change as well. The appearance of the character shifts enough to make her one of the new breed, but her identity is not disguised.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Form Of The Terrible Ancestors</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 62</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Form Of Another Breed</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Assuming the overtitle of the Dragon Emperor, the Dragon King grows into an enormous reptilian killing machine. Her Strength and Stamina scores both increase by an amount equal to her Path rating, and she gains one -1 health level and two -2 health levels. She also adds half of her Path rating to her bashing and lethal soaks. The character's natural weapons experience similarly deadly alterations, shown below. In this state, the character cannot speak, use weapons or wear armor. All clothing and attuned artifacts transform with the character, with armor losing its armor properties and weapons losing their weapon properties. The character may automatically succeed on any Valor rolls and gains a dot of Valor for the duration. Common Overtitle: Arilak, Leyata, Mokrelus.
   Speed Acc Damage Defense Rate
    Anklok
    Bite +0 +1 +7L +2 +0
    Claw +0 +2 +5L +0 +0
    Tail +0 +2 +4L +0 +0
    Mosok
    Bite +0 +3 +6L +2 +0
    Claw +0 +1 +4L +1 +0
    Tail -1 +3 +6B +2 +1
    Pterok
    Bite +0 +2 +6L +0 +0
    Wing +0 +3 +5B +2 +0
    Raptok
    Bite -1 +2 +5L +0 +0
    Claw +0 +1 +5L +0 +0</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Transformation Of The New Form</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Shaping Wood Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: Raptok
   Associated Virtue: Temperance
   The way of shaping wood is the way of ritual markings and names. Its teachings reveal the power of understanding, appreciating and controlling oneself. By opening himself to the legends deep in his soul, the Dragon King realizes who he has been, who he is now and what he can become.
   The Steps of this Path help the Dragon King to change shape into a deadlier or more useful creature. He first learns to refine and accentuate his bestial qualities, then to grow more physically versatile and powerful. Further teachings allow the adept to greatly enhance his resilience. He may even learn to temporarily become another breed of Dragon King. The master gains the ability to assume a legendary battle form. The Transcendent Dragon of Shaping Wood can become almost any creature of Creation.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were often professional hunters or warriors. Those who advanced along it were staunch allies, dedicated to themselves and their ideals. It was often considered good practice for successful Dragon Kings to study this Path before accepting positions of power and responsibility. Today, it is common among bestial Raptok in and around Rathess. As a result of its utility, a surprising number of older Dragon Kings have also studied the Path, and most sleepers have as well.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 63</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>Instant or indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Form Of The Terrible Ancestors</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Assuming the surname of a species, the Dragon King becomes a generic member of them. He keeps his regular traits and Steps but has the physical shape and qualities of his new species. He may also use the species's Physical Attributes and natural powers that do not rely on outside forces, though he may not understand exactly how to control all of his new capabilities (at Storyteller's discretion). The character is physically indistin-guishable from and possesses all of the mannerisms and instincts of his new species, though is still in full control himself.
   The Dragon King possesses the Ability to assume a number of different species (of the character's choice) equal to his Path rating. They may be any species that he has ever encountered, as long as they have Essence 2 or worse, can survive outside of the Wyld and are between the size of a tyrant lizard and a large cat. He may spend one experience point to swap out one species for another. Unique creatures cannot be copied.
   This Step's duration may be instant or indefinite, at the character's option. If she uses it to change to her original species, then she returns to her original form, the effects of age notwithstanding.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Life Through Death</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>6m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the Dragon King consumes the corpse of a sentient creature who has died within the last scene, she heals. At the conclusion of her meal, she recovers a number of health levels of lethal or bashing damage equal to her Path rating. The character may spend one Willpower during the meal to trade five levels of lethal or bashing healing to heal a single level of aggravated damage.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Consume The Mind</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>(Path rating) days</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Life Through Death</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the Dragon King consumes the brain of a sentient creature who has died within the last scene, she gains its memories.  If the target had an Essence score higher than the Dragon King's Path rating, then the Step fails. If the target was a mortal, the Dragon King may pay one Willpower when activating it to retain the memories indefinitely, without committed Essence. She can only hold the memories of one individual at a time.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Consume The Body</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>3m per dot</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>(Path rating) days</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Consume The Mind</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the Dragon King consumes the corpse of a sentient creature that has died within the last scene, she gains its body's strength and speed. She may increase her own Physical Attributes (prior to augmentations from breed or Charms) to those of the target, at a cost of three motes per dot. She may also consume and acquire any physical qualities (except Appearance) that the target possessed, such as claws or natural armor. These qualities are rated as though they were Wyld mutations (see Exalted, p. 288-290). Qualities as potent as a pox can be acquired automatically. Qualities as potent as afflictions cost three motes. Blights would cost six motes. Abominations cost nine motes. More potent physical qualities are either out of reach or subject to being reduced to the potency of an Abomination. Anything that requires motes of Essence to fuel cannot be acquired by this Step, nor can any qualities that rely on the target's Charms or Essence to function.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Jaws Of The Ash Dragon</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>8m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Consume The Body</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Step supplements a bite attack, causing it to ignore the target's armor soak. If the attack kills the target outright, or if the target is already dead, then this Step allows her to swallow all of the natural organic parts of the corpse, leaving behind only its equipment. In that case, the Dragon King may choose to reflexively activate any one other of this Path's Steps that require the consumption of a corpse. The reflexive power does not count as a Charm use but still carries the normal mote cost.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Consume Essence</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>1m or 10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Jaws Of The Ash Dragon</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the Dragon King consumes the corpse of a sentient creature who has died within the last scene, she gains its powers. The Dragon King regains a number of motes of Essence equal to 10 times the Essence score of the target. She also fully understands all of the target's Charms, to the extent that he understood them himself. The Dragon King may then spend an additional nine motes and one Willpower to choose one Charm or Step the target possessed, which she can then use as if she had mastered it herself. She must meet all the Charm's or Step's prerequisites and must pay the Charm's or Step's costs herself.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Consume Self</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Glorious Consumption Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Valor
   The way of glorious consumption is the way of eating ash. Its teachings reveal the latent power of the dead and the glory of hunger and greed. By opening herself to the dark ascension of spiritual consumption, the adherent grows more powerful as she defiles what has already been destroyed.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to feast on the dead and gain their power and knowledge for herself. She first learns to heal from the latent energies of dead flesh, then to steal memories. Further teachings allow the adept to acquire the physical properties of specific dead individuals. She may eventually learn to consume a person in a single bite. The master gains the ability to consume the Essence and powers of the dead. The Transcendent Dragon of Glorious Consumption can even evade death.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path contributed to the downfall of Rathess, where the Path of Glorious Consumption is still practiced today by the followers of the Ghoul King. These cultists ritually sacrifice and consume unwanted guests, animals and basically anything else they can get their teeth around. Fortunately, devotees of Han-Tha tend to be greedy and cowardly. They are thus difficult to motivate.
   Drawbacks: : Walking this Path involves eating corpses. The deceased must have been sentient, and almost all organs and limbs must be present. Eating a corpse is usually done over several days or weeks, but a dozen sick, hungry individuals could do it in a single meal. Sharing is permissible. This Path does not guard against disease.
   Worst of all, parts of powerful people upset their devourer's anatomy in several disgusting ways. Fueling a Step of this Path with the corpse of someone with an Essence score equal to or higher than the character's own causes an internal penalty to all rolls equal to the dot rating of the Step involved. Multiple instances are cumulative. These penalties can be offset for a single scene by spending one Willpower, but doing so inflicts one unsoakable level of aggravated damage for every -5 of the total penalty.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 64</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Consume Essence</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As the character lies dying, she invests her grave hunger into the fabric of the surrounding Essence. When her life ends, her body immediately consumes itself. Six ticks later, the Dragon King erupts from the reasonably intact corpse of any sentient being within one mile, consuming it in the process. The Dragon King's player may choose the most advantageous corpse, if multiple are available. The character returns with the Essence and Willpower that she had when she died and recovers enough damage to return her to her lowest -4 health level. As she rises, she may use her resurrection's host to fuel one of the other Charms on this Path (assuming that she may pay the other costs), potentially restoring additional damage or gaining a host's Charm.
   This Charm is ineffective if a suitable corpse does not exist within range, or if the Dragon King is killed by something so deadly that it completely bypasses her Dying health levels.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Sharing Of Blood</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 65</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By spending a miscellaneous action drinking the blood of a living creature as though it were wine, the Dragon King regains Essence. The amount gained is based on the creature providing blood. Animals grant one mote. Mortals provide two motes. Creatures with Essence 2 or higher provide three motes. Essence can be gained from a particular creature (Path rating) times during a scene. Each mote gained equates to a lethal health level lost by the target. Blood drained must be drunk within one scene to remain effective.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Palate For Shame</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 65</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>The Sharing Of Blood</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By slipping into the nightmares buried within any blood that she has tasted during the past scene, the Dragon King learns a desire or fear represented through one of the target's Intimacies. The character rolls (Intelligence + Socialize), adding (Path rating) successes and an external penalty equal to the target's Dodge MDV. Failure renders the target immune for the remainder of the scene. This Step always reveals lusts or fears of which the target is least proud first.
   The Dragon King's player adds dice equal to the roll's successes to all Presence, Performance, Investigation and Socialize rolls against the target that utilize revealed information. If the character knows with what information she wants to commune, she can seek it out deliberately. This Step does not automatically reveal who the target is.Using this Step counts as drinking the target's blood for the purposes of intoxication.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Finger Of Nightmares</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 65</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp, 1lhl</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious (unless using immaterial tendril)</keyword>
        <duration>(Stamina) actions</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>The Palate For Shame</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>To use this Step, the character must have at least one open, bleeding wound resulting from an attack that caused at least one lethal health level of damage. The Dragon King focuses on either fear or lust and extends from her wound a tentacle of inky blood, which she may use as a whip. It possesses all of the statistics of a normal whip, except that it is a natural part of the character, it does lethal damage, and it has a total damage bonus equal to the character's (Path rating + lethal health levels of damage currently suffered).
   During every action in which a target of the tentacle is "clinched", he must resist the fear or lust it exudes. If his MDV is less than the Dragon King's (Path rating x 2), then he must spend one Willpower to avoid immediately acting on the emotion. This is an unnatural mental influence.
   The tentacle dissolves after a number of actions equal to the character's Stamina. However, while the Step persists, she may reflexively spend another lethal health level to refill it with blood and vigor for (Stamina) additional actions. The whip is hungry, and any successful attack with it counts as the character drinking the target's blood.
   Dragon Kings with Path rating 4 or higher may create an immaterial tentacle, which may still influence material creatures' minds but cannot hold or damage them and does not drink their blood. It's also invisible to those who can't perceive the immaterial.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Blessed Tie That Binds</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 65</reference>
        <cost>12m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Servitude</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>The Finger Of Nightmares</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Except for its duration, and the minor effects below, this Step is mechanically identical to the Solar Charm Worshipful Lackey Acquisition (see Exalted, p. 205). However, it can only be enacted while the target is under the influence of the Finger of Nightmares and is only visible to those who can view the immaterial. Such onlookers perceive a small red tendril growing from the target's body and stretching in the Dragon King's direction. It cannot be physically removed. Finally, targets of this Step suffer a -1 internal penalty to Temperance and Valor rolls while it persists.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Oneness Of The Blood</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 66</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>The Blessed Tie That Binds</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Step is activated while someone in the character's presence knowingly consumes her blood in its pure form. The target (the drinker of the blood) gains the rapid and complete healing, resistance to disease and enhanced natural soak of the Exalted. Unfortunately, the Dragon King may at any time spend one mote and use a miscellaneous action to cause the blood to reject him, dealing one unsoakable level of lethal damage.
   Additionally, the target's dreams are extremely pleasant and satisfying, adding one die to his Conviction roll to regain Willpower upon awakening. Unfortunately, the Dragon King may also subtly influence the target with strange nightmares. Once each day, she may reflexively spend one mote and use a miscellaneous action to cause the next period of the target's sleep to count as a scene spent building an Intimacy toward any of the Dragon King's own Intimacies or her Motivation. At his option, the dreams may be intense enough to eliminate any Conviction roll to regain Willpower upon awakening altogether. Otherwise, the target must succeed on a (Wits + Integrity) roll just to notice the shift in Intimacies.
   Finally, the Dragon King may reflexively spend one mote and a miscellaneous action to intoxicate the target as though she were an adherent of this Path who had just partaken of her blood.
       Mortals remain affected by this Charm even after the Essence powering it is uncommitted. Beings with Essence 2 or higher remain affected only until the commitment is broken. Any target may attempt to reject the blood within them. Doing so costs one Willpower and deals one level of aggravated damage. The victim's player rolls (Stamina + Resistance) and adds her character's Essence as automatic successes. An external penalty applies equal to the Dragon King's (Path rating + Essence). On a success, the target vomits up a coagulated mass of writhing, tentacled blood that splashes to the ground with an unholy whine, ending the Step's effects.
   The Dragon King may use this Step on herself to receive its benefits. However, another Dragon King with a higher Essence score who has also used this Step on himself may then control the blood of the lesser. If two Dragon Kings who have used this Step on themselves have the same Essence score, then neither can affect the other in that way.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>The Multitude Of Onenesses</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Coagulated Eucharist Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the Coagulated Eucharist is the way of drinking blood. Its teachings reveal the power of invasive intimacy through fear and lust. By opening herself to the blissful freedom of shameless addiction, the adherent learns to control and be controlled and to find communion in the gory will of darkness.
   The Steps of this Path allow the adherent to manipulate emotionally and to be manipulated. She first learns to take pleasure and Essence from blood, then to taste the shame contained within. Further teachings allow the adept to create a deadly tentacle of blood and darkness. She may eventually learn to use the tentacle to solidly chain the hearts of others. The master gains the ability to make her blood into a parasite that can help her manipulate from a distance. The Transcendent Dragon of the Coagulated Eucharist can raise her Essence score higher than normal as she absorbs the alien will of darkness.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were leaders of dark cults in the far corners of Creation. Today, cults of this Path emerge suddenly and unpredictably, and it seems that some Dragon Kings inherit its teachings from the Underworld. Most of these cults lose themselves to disease or the Underworld, but some manage to evolve into deadly armies of blood-crazed zealots.
   Drawbacks: Though the Sharing of Blood makes drinking blood pleasurable and easy, vital fluids still carry disease. To those under the effects of this Path, they also carry darkness and inebriation. Drinking blood causes a cumulative -1 penalty to Temperance and Valor (minimum 0), unless an adherent's player succeeds on a Willpower roll at a difficulty equal to the blood donor's Essence. Drinking more total times than her Path rating within a scene causes this roll to fail automatically. Lost Virtue points return at a rate of one each per scene.
   Also, using any Step of this Path on anyone with a Compassion score less than the character's own counts as a scene building an Intimacy for the target based on lust or fear.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 67</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>Stackable</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>The Oneness Of The Blood</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King adds darkness to herself, in the form of an additional Motivation. He uses it in all ways like a normal Motivation. The Storyteller creates a Motivation concerning an extremely long-term goal involving fear and/or lust and incorporating the control of multiple people. It is unrelated to the character's original Motivation, seeming foreign or alien. The character's original Motivation has primacy when there is a conflict.
       Purchasing this Step also allows the character to raise her Essence score one higher than before, and to purchase this Step again, to a maximum of three times.
   Unfortunately, these enhanced statistics come from the power of the Underworld. The Dragon King must venture to the Underworld for 24 hours each month per purchase of this Step. The first purchase requires a shadowland. The second requires the Underworld proper. The third requires the Labyrinth itself. Deprived of access to the Underworld, the character loses any traits she should not possess until she returns.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Mechanically Integrated Attunement Meditation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 67</reference>
        <cost>1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King takes normal actions designed to attune to an artifact. Instead of investing Essence into the connection however, he forces onto himself internal changes designed to form a less mystical link.
   So long as the artifact has a rating no higher than his Essence, he may attune to it for free. However, he must dedicate a number of Willpower points equal to one third the artifact's commitment cost, rounded up (minimum one Willpower). If his temporary Willpower pool falls below that number, the attunement instantly breaks. The attunement will also break if the Dragon King leaves physical contact with the artifact for a full scene. The Dragon King cannot force complete harmonization to receive the magical material bonus from artifacts that are made of an unsuitable magical material.
   The Dragon King may use this Step to maintain a number of attunements equal to his Path rating. The amount of Willpower needed to maintain multiple attunements does not automatically increase with each new artifact. The same Willpower points can be used to power multiple artifacts.
   Artifacts attuned through the use of this Step that require Essence expenditures to use can and must be powered by Willpower also. The Dragon King substitutes one Willpower for up to three motes of Essence.
   This Step also allows mortals to attune to and activate artifacts using their Willpower. This Step does not allow anyone to attune to an artifact using both Essence and Willpower. It's either one or the other.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Semi-Organic Assemblage Program</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 68</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Mechanically Integrated Attunement Meditation</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Using his bones and nerves as tools, the character constructs, repairs and maintains artifacts that are surgically integrated into him with astounding speed and skill. Applicable artifacts must be a part of the character - non-functional without him and unusable by others without some surgical effort. With regard to the difficulty of his work, this Step temporarily reduces the artifact's effective rating by one, and its repair rating by two. An artifact's effective rating cannot be reduced below one by this, but its effective repair rating can be reduced to 0, in which case repair and maintenance conducts itself reflexively and automatically over the course of the scene. Finally, the character is in no danger at all from medical complications arising from integrated artifacts or surgery intended to implant them.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Skeletal Fusion Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 68</reference>
        <cost>6m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Semi-Organic Assemblage Program</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>As Essence welds metal to bone, (Path rating) of the Dragon King's attuned artifacts become part of his body. He cannot be disarmed of such artifacts, and they cannot be removed from his body against his will. Artifacts that are deliberately separated from the character (by throwing them, giving them away, etc), or become unattuned to him, are no longer a part of this Step's effects. This Step has no effect on artifacts with a rating higher than the character's Essence, but applicable artifacts can be transferred right off of an enemy's body or out of his hand.
   Weapons grafted by this Charm can be wielded with Martial Arts and count as natural attacks. Grafted armor's soak simultaneously counts as both armor soak and natural soak, whichever is more beneficial.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Magitechnological Transformation Kata</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 68</reference>
        <cost>6m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Skeletal Fusion Technique</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King's body transforms to hide attuned artifacts he possesses. While so hidden, the artifacts cannot be used, but they also cannot be detected by normal senses. Charms designed to analyze Essence patterns can potentially recognize the presence of concentrated Essence but cannot gather the number or details of artifacts. The character may reflexively produce or re-hide his hidden artifacts. If all of the Dragon King's artifacts are hidden, then the social penalty inflicted by this Path is halved and rounded down.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Neuro-Skeletal Attunement Interface</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 68</reference>
        <cost>6m, 2wp (see text)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Magitechnological Transformation Kata</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Using his nerves and bones as an interface, the Dragon King instantly attunes to any artifacts that he is touching and cannot be forcibly detuned from them by any power. If he attempts to force full harmonization with such artifacts, his player gains a number of bonus dice equal to the Dragon King's Path rating. Furthermore, if the character's Path rating equals or exceeds an affected artifact's rating, he becomes aware of all of an artifact's potential functions and how to activate them. Artifacts beyond five dots are counted as six dots (or potentially higher). Even if an affected artifact is too powerful to fully access, he gains a number of dice equal to his Path rating to Lore rolls designed to figure it out.
   If a touched artifact is attuned to another character when this Step is activated, then it can be forcefully detuned from her, so long as the Dragon King's Path rating exceeds the target's Essence. If an affected artifact is physically separated from the character, then the effects of the Step end with regard to the item.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Total Systemic Mechanization</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Technomorphic Transcendence Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Compassion
   The way of technomorphic transcendence is the way of cracking bones. Its teachings reveal the power of rationality and technological progress. By opening himself to the will to power through scientific augmentation and cold logic, the adherent learns to become the ultimate blend of Dragon King and machine.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to enhance himself through the use of artifacts and to become more like them. He first learns to power artifacts using cold focus in place of Essence, then to build and repair artifacts as a part of himself. Further teachings allow the adept to fuse artifacts to himself, making them a part of him. He may eventually learn to hide his artifacts within himself. The master gains the ability to instantly attune to artifacts, even if they are attuned to others. The Transcendent Dragon of Technomorphic Transcendence can become completely mechanical, rapidly regaining Willpower and becoming immune to mental influence.
   During the First Age, walkers of this Path were hermits whose study of mechanical remorselessness eventually led them to attempt wild schemes intended to further psychopathic agendas. Today, there are no known adherents to this Path, but it is said that true automata can occasionally enlighten Dragon Kings into its lessons, and cleverly disguised sutras explaining its techniques are currently being deciphered by both Lookshy and the Realm.
   Drawbacks: Using surgery to implant biomagic artifacts typically requires a sophisticated laboratory (Resources 4), as well as an extended action requiring multiple (Intelligence + [Lower of Lore, Medicine or Occult]) rolls. See the descriptions of specific artifacts for details.
   The scientific detachment of this style does not react well to feelings and does not play well with others. A penalty to Compassion and social rolls is applied to any character using a Step of this Path. The penalty is equal to the highest Path rating of the Technomorphic Transcendence Path Steps currently active.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 68</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Neuro-Skeletal Attunement Interface</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>While the Step is active, the character becomes fully emotionally detached and mechanical. She never makes Compassion rolls nor fails other Virtue rolls.
   The Dragon King cannot spend Willpower on effects that are not related to Steps, such as activating Virtues. However, the character regains one Willpower each tick.
   The Dragon King also becomes immune to mental influence of all kinds.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Smoldering Hatred</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 69</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple or Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Amplifying anger until it boils over, this Step supplements a social attack designed to create an Intimacy based on anger or hatred or to erode a positive Intimacy in a person or group with Magnitude no greater than the Dragon King's Path rating. If the attack is successful, a target gains a bonus die to all attack and damage rolls for the remainder of the scene. Also, he must fight in some fashion or must spend two Willpower to remain peaceful. This is an unnatural mental influence.
   The character may target herself with this Step as a simple action (Speed 6, DV -1), even in combat.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Blistering Execration</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 69</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Smoldering Hatred</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Glowing with hatred, the Dragon King's hand-to-hand attacks against a particular target deal aggravated damage. When this Step is first purchased, the Dragon King's player chooses the target. It must be a sentient creature to whom she possesses an Intimacy involving anger or hatred. The target can later be changed to a different qualifying creature for one experience point. If the Dragon King destroys her target, then switching to a new one is free. If at any point the Character does not possess a correct Intimacy toward her target, then this Step won't work.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Fires Of Retribution</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 69</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Elemental</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Blistering Execration</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King's vengeance becomes flame that lashes out to deal (Path rating) dice of lethal damage to any character that successfully attacks her in hand-to-hand combat. This damage cannot be parried or dodged but can be soaked normally. As an added bonus, the character becomes immune to non-magical fire while the Step is active.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Breath Of Damnation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 69</reference>
        <cost>1m per two dice</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Elemental</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Fires Of Retribution</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King exhales a wicked gout of flame that deals a base two dice of lethal damage for every mote spent. The attack is aimed using (Dexterity + Athletics or Thrown), fires out to a maximum range equal to (Path rating) yards and has an accuracy bonus equal to the character's Path Rating. Extra successes add to damage normally. The character may make a sweeping attack, targeting multiple characters within range, which causes multiple-action penalties as appropriate. The base damage is then divided by the total number of targets. Any attempt to parry the attack using a weapon not built of the magical materials does not work and destroys the weapon. The Dragon King may spend a maximum of (Path rating) motes powering this Step.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Sermon Of Elemental Ruination</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 69</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Breath Of Damnation</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King calls for the destruction of everything nearby with a social attack using Performance that targets a group with a Magnitude no greater than the Dragon King's Path rating and within a surrounding area of (Path rating x 20) yards. Everyone and everything who fails to defend against the attack is consumed by the lust for destruction. All nearby spirits, including little gods, bend an ear to the sermon, and the area becomes dark and cursed. All fires within range become pyre flame. All still water within range becomes diseased. The wind turns cold and turbulent, and smoldering ash fills the air. The earth shakes. Cliff sides break apart, and deadly fissures rip themselves open. Animals turn violent and attack their masters. Plants wilt and begin to lose their leaves, quickly dying. The area itself becomes an environmental hazard equivalent to a severe sandstorm (see Exalted, p. 131).
   All nearby characters who fail to defend suffer an unnatural mental influence that induces them to destroy everything nearby. Affected characters do not ignore each other in their rage, but they tend to save each other for last. Things or people for whom there can be found preexisting hatred or aggression will be the first to be destroyed. Spending two Willpower will calm the mad rage to a manageable level. The Dragon King gains five motes of Essence whenever something significant to which he has an Intimacy of hate or rage is destroyed.
   By spending an additional point of Willpower when enacting this Step, the Dragon King may permanently convert a successfully affected fire elemental with an Essence score lower than her Path Rating into the equivalent of a pyre flame elemental. Altering an elemental in this way has severe effects on the being's Motivation. They usually come to hate all things, especially fire. The change often quickly adjusts his Virtues to favor Conviction and Valor over Compassion and Temperance. These "elementals" cannot understand what has happened to them unless it is thoroughly explained and are often confused and pliable, finding aesthetic joy and fulfillment in the wondrous Steps of this Path. Multiple Willpower points can be spent to fuel the change of multiple fire elementals.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Pyric Mantle Of Destruction</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Ecstatic Armageddon Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Temperance
   The way of the ecstatic Armageddon is the way of breathing pyre flame. Its teachings reveal the power and glory of destruction for hate's sake. By opening herself to the glory of bloodlust and rage, the adherent learns to consume her enemies in a fire that never dies.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to kill and destroy on a devastating scale. She first learns to harness the rage of herself and others for combat, then to destroy a single enemy using aggravated damage. Further teachings allow the adept to burn indiscriminately and to lash out when struck. She may eventually learn to breathe a deadly stream of flame. The master gains the ability to stir up violence in every aspect of the surrounding area. The Transcendent Dragon of Ecstatic Armageddon can instantly summon up a horde of minions and spreads pyre flame everywhere she goes.
   Today, the Ecstatic Armageddon Path springs up where hate calls its unholy name loud enough to rattle the bones of the Neverborn. Fortunately, it usually consumes those who wish to learn it before they can get very far.
   Drawbacks: Wherever any of the Steps of this Path are active, there are flames. Any dry combustibles touching the character catch fire, and things within 10 yards may also. It's impos-sible to predict what will catch fire, but things that are most likely to burn quickly and spread the flame tend to be the first to go.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 70</reference>
        <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Sermon Of Elemental Ruination</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King becomes an avatar of obliteration. She is engulfed in a bonfire of pyre flame that moves with her and clings to all things that touch it or pass through it. Those things which only skirt the edge of the pyre flame are affected by a two-die amount (see the "Pyre Flame" sidebar). Those attacking it with a melee weapon are affected by a four-die amount. Those attempting to attack the character with natural weapons are affected by a six-die amount, which is the maximum from this effect. The pyre-flame bonfire regenerates itself, so the Dragon King need never worry about running out. The character herself is immune to mundane fire and pyre flame while the Step is active, and she may grasp a two-die amount of pyre flame and hurl it, using (Dexterity + Thrown) and the attack statistics below. Furthermore, all of the character's hand-to-hand attacks deliver a two-die amount of pyre flame, and all of the normal flame attacks of this Path's earlier Steps can become pyre flame attacks at her option. Instead of doing their normal damage, she may choose to have them inflict pyre flame upon their target, covering him in an amount that deals damage equal to the normal damage of the attack.
   What's more, from the green flame emerges a unit of creatures made up of tiny forbidden gods, spontaneous faux "elementals" based on the Dark Paths' elements and strange things that dwell in shadows, all twisted by hate and fueled by the vitriolic Essence of the pyre. They have a Magnitude of (Path rating - 2) and possess stats equivalent to those of green soldiers (see Exalted, p. 279). They have the following mass combat stats: Drill 0, Endurance 2, Might 0, Close Combat Rating 2, Close Combat Damage 2, Morale (Path rating -3). They come with no special characters and cannot act independently of a mass combat setting. They are, however, immune to the Dragon King's pyre flame. Attacking the Dragon King's unit does not require entering into the radius of her pyre flame, but targeting her specifically would, at least with a hand-to-hand attack. If this army is destroyed, the character cannot summon up a new one until she travels at least one mile distant or one full day passes.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Rage In The Ropes Of Dukkha</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 71</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1ahl per success</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>For every three motes and one aggravated health level sacrificed, the Dragon King gains a success on the roll for any action. The character cannot channel through a Virtue to enhance an action that benefits from this Step. Characters with sufficient Essence can use this Charm to do as much damage to themselves as they want, but they cannot benefit from more successes than their Path rating.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Pierce The Black Veil Of Anicca</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 71</reference>
        <cost>6m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Rage In The Ropes Of Dukkha</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The character perceives the pale fire of the Void burning within the hearts of all sentient creatures. He can discern whether anyone that he perceives has an Intimacy involving faith or devotion to a religion or philosophy and whether their Motivation involves devotion to a religion or philosophy. The fire also identifies Essence scores, discerns Exalts from non-Exalts, detects whether someone is unaging and points out whether those viewed consist of or spend death Essence.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Cling To The Loving Embrace Of Atman</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 72</reference>
        <cost>8m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>(Stamina) days</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Pierce The Black Veil Of Anicca</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King becomes a ghost. He loses access to all powers not normally available to ghosts, except for those of this Path. He retains all of his other statistics and may even learn ghost Arcanoi Charms as though he were a normal one of them. He retains the Ability to use such Arcanoi whenever he enters ghost form or if he dies and becomes one once and for all.
   The character must be incapacitated with lethal or aggravated damage to use the Step. His body can't be healed while the Step is active. If the body is damaged, it begins dying. If it dies, the character will remain a ghost forever.
   Upon becoming a ghost, the Dragon King heals a number of health levels equal to his Path rating, which becomes his maximum possible level of health. While his body survives, he cannot be healed further than that by any means. Upon returning to his body, he is once again incapacitated. If the character's ghostly self is destroyed while this Step persists, then he returns to his body but loses all of his remaining Willpower points and suffers one level of lethal damage, which causes him to begin dying. The same fate awaits him if, for any reason, this Step is prematurely ended while he is not in physical contact with his body.
   The Dragon King's body will die after (Stamina) days without its soul.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Be Sticks In The Sacred Fire Of Nirvana</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 72</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive or Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Cling To The Loving Embrace Of Atman</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Step supplements a social attack designed to instill or promote an Intimacy of devotion toward a religion or philosophical ideal. The attack's effects become an unnatural mental influence. A target that possesses or gains the Intimacy recovers a point of Willpower and gains a temporary dot of Valor. A target whose Motivation corresponds with the attack is granted a temporary Valor score of 6. She also gains points of temporary Willpower and suffers levels of aggravated damage equal to the (Threshold of the attack roll + 1).  These Willpower points can exceed the normal maximum, but excess Willpower fades at the end of the scene.
   Anyone who is successfully targeted by this Step may choose to sacrifice her life for the Dragon King. The target's life force becomes a shower of cold, blue flames, which flood into the character's heart and dance around his body. Targets whose Motivation involves religious devotion provide (Essence rating) flames. Others provide one flame per dot of Essence. These flames last until the end of the scene. Anyone who is outright killed by the damage of this Step is considered to have sacrificed her life in this way.
   The Dragon King may spend the flames as though they were motes of Essence. Furthermore, if the character uses the flames to fuel the first Step of this Path, then he does not have to sacrifice any health levels to use it.
   The character may potentially target a social unit with a Magnitude no greater than his (Path rating - 3), and every member of the unit may potentially sacrifice themselves to provide him with soul flames. The unit (minus any special or heroic characters) acts as its leader does.
   The Dragon King may reflexively use this Step on himself. Should he martr himself while using it, he gains double the normal number of flames and may complete any (non-dramatic) actions that he is taking before perishing.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Lament The 5,000 Poison Bhumi Of The Bodhisattva</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 72</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Be Sticks In The Sacred Fire Of Nirvana</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Step allows the character to take Shadowlands Circle Necromancy actions, even if he happens to be a ghost as a result of Cling to the Loving Embrace of Atman.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Murder Samsara &amp; Wear Her Sad Robes</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <tree>
            <name>The Tormented Bodhisattva Path</name>
            <description>Favored Breed: None
   Anathema Virtue: Conviction
   The way of the tormented bodhisattva is the way of the Void mandala. Its teachings reveal the power of religious devotion and sacrifice for its own sake. By opening himself to the terrible, terrifying, inevitable end, the adherent conquers death even as he becomes its terrified thrall.
   The Steps of this Path help the adherent to internalize and manipulate death and destructive religious devotion. He first learns to sacrifice his life force to succeed, then to sense the slow decay within the life force of others. Further teachings allow the adept to leave his physical body as a ghost. He may eventually learn to enflame the power of devotion and sacrifice within others for his own power. The master gains the ability to use Iron Circle Necromancy. The Transcendent Dragon of the Tormented Bodhisattva becomes a walking avatar of death, waiting, terrified, for the perfect moment to sacrifice himself forever to bring the Void to his enemies.
   During the First Age, a handful of Raptok were born with a strange affinity for this Path. They grew in power and, eventually, several became sleepers. Today, a few enlightened Dragon Kings have begun stirring up religious fervor and inciting wars. It seems likely that at least one of the sleepers has awoken and is spreading his twisted faith.
   Drawbacks: This Path revolves around devotion and martyrdom. As one progresses along the Path, it becomes harder to resist the urge to sacrifice oneself to the cause. Given an opportunity to give his life in service to the Tormented Bodhisattva Path, an adherent's player must fail a Conviction check in order for his character to avoid playing martyr so long as doing so will also bring death to the Path's enemies.</description>
        </tree>
        <reference>Scroll of Fallen Races, page 72</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>6</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Lament The 5,000 Poison Bhumi Of The Bodhisattva</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The Dragon King is immune to the effects of Lethe and need never roll to resist it. This is a perfect effect. He exudes a mobile shadowland around himself out to 500 yards. When anyone dies within it, he senses it, gaining information about the deceased as though he had observed her with Pierce the Black Veil of Anicca. He also gains a mote, as his body summons and absorbs frozen wisps of death Essence.
   Worse still, there is always a gate into the Labyrinth somewhere within the character's shadowland. Sometimes it is tiny - sometimes large enough for a man to enter. If the Dragon King tarries in one place, bad things will eventually emerge.
   Worst of all, when the character decides the time is right, he may decide his death (or dissolution of his ghostly form) shall finally send him to Oblivion forever. The unholy glory of this sacrifice causes a brilliant blue explosion of soul fire that levels everything within (Essence) miles, obliterating all structures not reinforced by the magical materials, and dealing 10 unsoakable levels of aggravated damage to creatures caught in the area. The shadowland then settles in place, filling the affected area permanently. The decision to sacrifice himself to Oblivion cannot be coerced through unnatural mental influence.</description>
    </charms>
</body>