<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body type="charms">
   <charms>
      <name>Demon-Wracking Shout</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Akuma</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
      </allowed>
      <category>
         <name>Adorjan</name>
      </category>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Infernals, page 147</reference>
      <cost>50m, 5ahl</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <type>Simple</type>
      <keyword>Blasphemy</keyword>
      <keyword>Compulsion</keyword>
      <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         The death cry of Lilike, fetich soul of the River of Torments, armed her murderer with a horrid bane against the newly incarnated Adorjan. Accordingly, this Charm may be learned by Solars, Lunars and Sidereals for 16 experience points as though the Chosen were a member of the Eclipse Caste. No teacher is necessary if the character has ever heard the Charm used. Gods and demons who have heard the Charm can teach it, though they can't actually learn it themselves.
         The Demon-Wracking Shout is a cry that exceeds all others, both in volume and in the scope of its anguish. As this Charm activates, a piece of the Exalt's soul tears off and pours from his mouth as a screaming wind that courses over the battlefield like Adorjan herself. Demons within a radius of one mile suffer levels of unsoakable aggravated damage equal to the Exalt's Essence rating. Those killed join the scream, bodies remaining upright and shrieking as bloody streamers of Essence pour from their dead mouths for a heartbeat before the gale disintegrates them. Any First Circle demon who survives suffers an irresistible Compulsion to flee the area and not return for five days. Until then, they treat efforts to make them return as unacceptable orders. Second and Third Circle survivors also feel this Compulsion but may resist by spending five Willpower. Demons descended from Adorjan can’t resist regardless of their circle. All beings within the radius suffer deafness as a Crippling effect, though hearing returns to Essence users at the end of the scene. Souls of non-Yozi Primordials caught in the radius suffer as demons do, though souls transformed into non-spirit states of existence like demesnes or artifacts do not.
         Adorjan herself (along with any other who has learned Hateful Wretched Noise) suffers no damage from the Charm, but its Compulsion exorcises her as readily as her progeny. She also suffers an Emotion effect that forces her to instantly develop an Intimacy of love toward the character who dared echo her slain fetich, replacing any existing Intimacy to the character based on another emotional context. Lilike's murderer Marus came to regret the love of Adorjan and vainly sought to earnher hatred until his terrible death. Those who wield this Charm against her must never forget what her love means.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Soul-Enlightening Beneficence</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Scroll of the Monk, page 19</reference>
      <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Lore</name>
         <value>4</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
      <keyword>Enlightening</keyword>
      <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
      <keyword>Touch</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Essence-Lending Method</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         This variation on the better known Power-Awarding Prana (see Exalted, p. 218) immediately and permanently blasts open a willing mortal's doors of perception, opening him to the world's currents of Essence. Soul-Enlightening Beneficence requires a short ceremony to steel both donor and recipient for the awesome forces they shall unleash. The ceremony takes whatever form the participants feel is appropriate to solemnize the event. Then the mortal and the Exalt simply touch - and the cataract of Essence flooding through the recipient's soul knocks him out for (5 - his Stamina) hours. The recipient also trades one permanent dot of Willpower for another point of permanent Essence. After the character recovers, however, he possesses his own Essence pool.
         Like Touch of Divinity, this Charm offers no benefit to beings who already channel Essence. The donor merely transfers 15 motes of his own Essence.
         All types of Celestial (and Abyssal and Infernal) Exalts possess a variation of Soul-Enlightening Beneficence. The recipient gains an affinity for the source of the Exalt's power, like that granted by Touch of Divinity, which other Essence-sensing creatures can perceive.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Pasiap's Humility</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 194</reference>
      <cost>4m</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>2</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Reflexive</type>
      <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
      <duration>One scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Pasiap's humble nature caused him to remain with his disciples after the other Immaculate Dragons left Creation and the cycle of reincarnation behind. In learning his humility, an Immaculate monk achieves the necessary recognition that the world is wider - and deeper - than she may have previously known.
         Activating this Charm lets the Dragon-Blood see immaterial spirits as though they were material and manifest. Unfortunately, use of this Charm renders the physical world more difficult to perceive. Immaculates practicing Pasiap's Humility suffer a -2 internal penalty to all actions intended to affect any corporeal target, even a materialized spirit. If necessary, monks can refocus their attentions on the real world as an unrolled miscellaneous action, ending the Charm early.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Moment Of Daana'd</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 194</reference>
      <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Simple</type>
      <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
      <keyword>Enlightening</keyword>
      <duration>One scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Pasiap's Humility</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         It was the hands of Daana'd that shut the gates of the Underworld, forcing the Anathema's souls to remain forever in the dark as punishment for their evil. That great feat is part of what guides the Immaculate Order on its contemporary mission: to correct those souls and spirits who stray, seeing that such wayward creatures suffer the proper punishment.
         As it is difficult to punish an opponent that cannot be touched, Moment of Daana'd allows an Immaculate to walk in the mortal and spirit worlds simultaneously. When this Charm is active, a monk can interact physically with dematerialized spirits as if they were solid. Palm strikes and knife-hand blows that would normally pass through the god or demon connect as if the target were flesh and blood.
         Monks must still utilize Pasiap's Humility if they wish to see their targets, however. Additionally, practicing the Moment of Daana'd helps prevent a monk from being overwhelmed by Pasiap's Humility, eliminating the -2 penalty while both Charms are active.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Walker-Among-Irises Perception</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 195</reference>
      <cost>4m</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>2</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Simple</type>
      <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
      <duration>One scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>This Charm is functionally identical to Pasiap's Humility, except that immaterial creatures and spirits appear not in their true forms, but as god-shaped silhouettes, filled with an endless field of blossoming irises. With this Charm, irises constantly grow at the edge of the martial artist's vision, providing the -2 internal penalty.</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Iris-Bulb Discourse</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 195</reference>
      <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Reflexive (Step 1 or 2)</type>
      <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
      <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
      <keyword>Enlightening</keyword>
      <duration>One scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Walker-Among-Irises Perception</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Though this Charm is nearly identical to Moment of Daana'd, its use carries with it some additional effects and connotations. First, this technique is obvious when in use because large, foot-wide irises blossom from wherever the martial artist steps, shattering into a cloud of purple-black Essence and sweet scent after a few moments or if someone touches them.
         More importantly, this Charm was developed in a period after the Dragon-Blooded had betrayed and killed the Solar Exalted, their Heaven-mandated kings and lords. It was also before the Immaculate Order had the influence to restructure the relevant portions of the Celestial and Terrestrial Bureaucracies. During this period, the relationship between the Shogunate and the gods was in constant  ux, so martial artists created for themselves an advantage.
         In addition to making a martial artist able to strike and harm immaterial spirits, the practitioner of the Iris-Bulb Discourse increases her MDVs by the difference between her Essence and any present god or elemental with less Essence. Most members of the Bureaucracies take umbrage at such presumption, so when the martial artist is confronted by a god or elemental with greater Essence, that entity gains a similar benefit.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Tiger-And-Bear Awareness</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 195</reference>
      <cost>6m</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Reflexive (Step 2)</type>
      <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
      <duration>One scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         The martial artist practicing this Charm is aware of all that surrounds him. He respires wisdom, and nothing escapes his notice. To an observer, the martial artist appears to walk more lightly on his feet, and the winds seems to whisper in his ears.
         For the duration of the Charm, the martial artist is automatically aware of all beings within a number of yards equal to his Essence, unless an entity is expending Essence in an effort to conceal itself. Additionally, learning this Charm brings with it a sort of danger sense. A martial artist who knows Tiger-and-Bear Awareness can activate it Reflexively when subject to a sneak attack in order to automatically notice the assault.
         This Charm does not grant the ability to see immaterial spirits or dematerialized elementals in the vicinity.
      </description>
      <errata>
         <todo>replace</todo>
         <date>14-11-2010</date>
         <reference>Scroll of Errata, page 37</reference>
         <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
         <keyword>Leader</keyword>
         <errText>This Charm fails against supernatural concealment of any kind.</errText>
      </errata>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Tiger-And-Bear Unity</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 195</reference>
      <cost>4m, 1wp</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>4</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Supple-mental</type>
      <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
      <keyword>Enlightening</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Tiger-And-Bear Awareness</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         As she lets the Essence of Creation flow through her, the martial artist flows through it. As they are already one, she cannot fail to strike her target true and with great precision.
         Attacks supplemented by this Charm gain a number of automatic successes equal to no more than the attacker's Martial Arts score. She chooses the exact number of successes to apply, minimum zero, after Step Six of combat resolution, allowing her to make her blow as devastating or subtle as she likes.
      </description>
      <errata>
         <todo>replace</todo>
         <date>14-11-2010</date>
         <reference>Scroll of Errata, page 38</reference>
         <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
         <keyword>Enlightening</keyword>
         <keyword>Leader</keyword>
         <errText>This Charm applies successes in Step 4 (not Step 6).</errText>
      </errata>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Flowing Kata Form</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Ink Monkeys, vol. 11</reference>
      <cost>6m+ [1wp per Form]</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Simple</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>One Scene</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Two Complete Non-Terrestrial Styles</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Grandmasters understand that all principles are connected and all fighting styles express different petals of the same Perfected Lotus. Flowing Kata Form expresses this principle as one of the rare Celestial Martial Arts Charms unconnected to any style. Invoking it requires a commitment of at least six motes. So long as the Charm remains active and the martial artist has no Form-Type Charms active, he can pay one Willpower (and any non-mote costs) to reflexively activate any known Martial Arts Form-Type Charm with a mote cost less than the number of motes committed to Flowing Kata Form. This Willpower surcharge does not apply the first time a martial artist invokes a Form Charm this way each scene.
         Activating a Form-Type Charm via Flowing Kata Form doesn't count as a Charm activation or cost motes, though Dragon-Blooded still have to roll to invoke a Celestial Martial Arts Form. Forms turned on this way inhibit activation of other Form-Type Charms as normal for the keyword. Even magic that allows multiple Form-Type Charms to coexist does not allow reflexive invocation while using another Form. Characters with "multi-Form" magic remain free to stack Forms by conventionally activating them.
         There is no limit on how often a martial artist can reflexively adopt a new Form beyond the Willpower cost to do so, making it possible to use one Form to help an attack hit and then swapping to another to enhance the attack if it hits. Enabling a flexible fighting style that changes tactics without warning is the very reason Flowing Kata Form exists.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Swallowing The Lotus Root</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Akuma</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Dreams of the First Age: Lords of Creation, page 59</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>2</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Permanent</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         The greatest among the Exalted find it no great feat to master the arts of their subordinates. The experience cost of Terrestrial Martial Arts Charms is reduced to 4xp, or 5xp if Martial Arts is not a Caste or Favored Ability (or if the character has no Favored Abilities, as in the case of Alchemi-cals), and their training time is halved. During character creation, Terrestrial Martial Arts Charms cost half as much as native Charms, meaning that each starting Charm (or Charm purchased with bonus points) allocated to such a style provides two Charms instead. As a final benefit, the character no longer needs to pay a surcharge when using elementally aspected Terrestrial Martial Arts styles. Should a character who already knows Terrestrial Martial Arts learn this Charm, the experience cost of those Charms is retroactively lowered and the character is refunded the difference.
         This is a stand-alone Celestial Martial Arts Charm, which may only be learned by Celestial Exalted and akuma. Non-Solar Exalted know the Charm by different names; Abyssals call it Blood-Soaked Lotus Roots, while the Green Sun Princes know it as Roots of the Brass Lotus and Sidereals have dubbed it Perfected Lotus Mastery. Lunar Exalted know the Charm as Terrestrial Bloodline Integration.
         Alchemical Exalted achieve an identical effect through the use of a Perfected Lotus Matrix submodule called Lotus Filament Conduction (Essence 2; 6xp).
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>(Elemental) Style Formulation</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Dragon-Blooded, page 189</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Martial Arts</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>2</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
      <duration>
      </duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Mastery Of One Terrestrial Style</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Once a Dragon-Blood has completely mastered a Terrestrial style, she may shape her Essence skillfully enough to mimic the elemental nature of that style's elemental aspect. When using Terrestrial martial arts Charms with that affinity, she pays no elemental surcharge.
         Water-aspected Dragon-Blooded retain the unique ability to pay no surcharge on any Terrestrial styles. Using this Charm to emulate water Essence does not eliminate the need to pay surcharge on any styles, though - only on Terrestrial styles that are specifically Water-aspected (such as Terrestrial Hero Style).
         Note that this technique for overcoming elemental boundaries is inferior to that of studying the Glorious Dragon Styles, which can provide one with a far more complete mastery of one such element.
      </description>
      <errata>
         <todo>replace</todo>
         <date>14-11-2010</date>
         <reference>Scroll of Errata, page 37</reference>
         <errText>This is a general Terrestrial Martial Arts Charm and may be learned by non-Dragon-Blooded.</errText>
      </errata>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Devonian Absorption</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Akuma</ok>
         <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
         <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Mortals</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 2 - Black and White Treatises, page 22</reference>
      <cost>50m, 5ahl</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Lore</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Permanent</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Terrestrial Circle Sorcery</name>
      </prerequest>
      <prerequest>
         <name>5+ spells</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Each Absorption - Devonian, Salinan or Silurian - offers characters a choice of special abilities. The player picks two. Storytellers can invent more powers for the three Absorptions, if they like. If this benefit seems too powerful for a series, Storytellers can restrict characters to one power per Absorption, or raise the Essence prerequisite to 6.
         A Devonian master must believe in the repeatable, calculable nature of Essence and the power of careful observation, logic and experiment. She also must conduct extensive experiments in natural and supernatural science, adding a further minimum of Lore 3.
         • Manse and artifact attunements are repeatable experiments. With a successful (Intelligence + Lore) roll, difficulty ([Manse or Artifact rating] x 2), the sorcerer can attune to such a thing in 20 ticks instead of the usual 20 minutes or so. If she ever succeeds on the roll for a given object, thereafter she always succeeds again.
         • When a Devonian master analyzes a supernatural effect, her player's (Intelligence + Occult) roll becomes extended. Each roll represents a week of research and experiment. Given time, she can probably puzzle out any supernatural effect. A single botched roll means the analysis ends in failure - even the Absorption cannot solve every puzzle of Essence - and Excellencies do not apply. The gradual, systematic analysis rules out the flashes of supernatural genius the Excellencies represent.
         • Deep study of each spell helps a Devonian master cast spells despite interruptions. When the character's Shape Sorcery action is disrupted, she may reflexively apply any Occult Excellency she knows to the (Wits + Occult) roll to carry on with spellcasting.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Salinan Absorption</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Akuma</ok>
         <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
         <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Mortals</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 2 - Black and White Treatises, page 22</reference>
      <cost>50m, 5ahl</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Awareness</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Permanent</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Terrestrial Circle Sorcery</name>
      </prerequest>
      <prerequest>
         <name>5+ spells</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Each Absorption - Devonian, Salinan or Silurian - offers characters a choice of special abilities. The player picks two. Storytellers can invent more powers for the three Absorptions, if they like. If this benefit seems too powerful for a series, Storytellers can restrict characters to one power per Absorption, or raise the Essence prerequisite to 6.
         A Salinan master demonstrates belief that everyone is an individual thought in a universal consciousness, and that all Essence flows most freely in its natural state. Such characters can see meaning and connections in the most surprising things. A Salinan master requires at least Awareness 3 to represent her sensitivity to Creation.
         • Understanding that her self is simultaneously hers alone and part of Creation's own nonlocal consciousness, the Salinan master can use Emerald Countermagic against any unnatural mental influence, as long as it is backed by an Essence or Artifact rating no higher than half her own (round up).
         • A Salinan master can pull information from nowhere (or maybe from the Salinan Working). Whenever his player rolls a threshold of five successes on any Perception or Intelligence roll, the Storyteller imparts a piece of relevant, important information.
         • Everything is connected to everything else. A Salinan master can apply Creation's wholeness to arcane links. She can substitute one arcane link for any other to the same subject, no matter what a spell's description says. (She could use a lock of a victim's hair, for instance, rather than the required drop of his blood.) What's more, with three different arcane links to a person or place, she can use them to target any spell.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Silurian Absorption</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Alchemicals</ok>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Akuma</ok>
         <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
         <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
         <ok>Green Sun Princes</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Mortals</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 2 - Black and White Treatises, page 22</reference>
      <cost>50m, 5ahl</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Linguistics</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Permanent</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Terrestrial Circle Sorcery</name>
      </prerequest>
      <prerequest>
         <name>5+ spells</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>
         Each Absorption - Devonian, Salinan or Silurian - offers characters a choice of special abilities. The player picks two. Storytellers can invent more powers for the three Absorptions, if they like. If this benefit seems too powerful for a series, Storytellers can restrict characters to one power per Absorption, or raise the Essence prerequisite to 6.
         A Silurian master believes Creation is an arbitrary system of interacting symbols that he can manipulate through its syntax. These sorcerers tend to see everything in terms of symbols and communication: map and territory, call and response, rhetoric and games. Their Absorption requires Linguistics 3 or better.
         • A Silurian master can block the powers of the Fair Folk, who likewise treat Creation as a fiction they change at will. A Silurian master can use Emerald Countermagic against any Fair Folk Charm or glamour backed by Essence no higher than her own (round up).
         • Silurian masters excel at recombining the symbolic components of spells. The character can invent new versions of spells he knows, changing one aspect of its manifestation such as the shape of its area, its manifested substance or its elemental source - but the Essence cost stays the same and the new version cannot offer any net advantage. (For instance, Death of Silver Butterflies offers financial advantage, but doesn't make the spell more effective as a spell.) The variation costs the character half the experience of learning a truly new spell. Characters who don't already know the original spell or lack Silurian training pay full cost for the variant spell.
         • A Silurian master can break symbolic connections to herself. If her player succeeds at a reflexive (Wits + Essence) roll, with a difficulty of the attacking sorcerer's Essence, the character breaks the arcane link before the spell can affect her.
      </description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Terrestrial Circle Sorcery</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
         <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Mortals</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Exalted, page 220</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Abyssals</ok>
            <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
            <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
            <ok>Mortals</ok>
            <ok>Sidereals</ok>
            <ok>Solars</ok>
            <ok>Spirits</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Intelligence</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Lunars</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>The Exalted shape the Essence of the world. This Charm lets the character hone her will to the razor-sharp edge necessary to perform magic of the so-called First Circle - a power infinitely greater than mortal thaumaturgy. This magic can affect up to a few hundred individuals at a time, and its spells take only a few moments to cast. This Charm allows the character to take Terrestrial Circle Sorcery actions (see p. 252).</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Celestial Circle Sorcery</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Exalted, page 220</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>4</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Abyssals</ok>
            <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
            <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
            <ok>Mortals</ok>
            <ok>Sidereals</ok>
            <ok>Solars</ok>
            <ok>Spirits</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Intelligence</name>
         <value>4</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Lunars</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>4</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Terrestrial Circle Sorcery</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>Celestial Circle Sorcery can slay thousands, level fortresses and bind Second Circle demons to the Exalt's will. Only the Celestial Exalted can master this powerful sorcerous initiation. This Charm permits the character to take Celestial Circle Sorcery actions (see p. 252).</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Solar Circle Sorcery</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Exalted, page 221</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Celestial Circle Sorcery</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>The sorcery reserved for the character is a work of perfection and adamant. The spells of Solar Circle Sorcery are awesome beyond words - they can bring life to regions or slay entire armies. This Charm permits the character to take Solar Circle Sorcery actions (see p. 252).</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Shadowlands Circle Necromancy</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
         <ok>Lunars</ok>
         <ok>Mortals</ok>
         <ok>Sidereals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
         <ok>Spirits</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Abyssals, page 162</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Abyssals</ok>
            <ok>Dragon-Blooded</ok>
            <ok>Dragon Kings</ok>
            <ok>Mortals</ok>
            <ok>Sidereals</ok>
            <ok>Solars</ok>
            <ok>Spirits</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Intelligence</name>
         <value>3</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
         <allowed>
            <ok>Lunars</ok>
         </allowed>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>3</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>None</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>This Charm permits the character to take Shadowlands Circle Necromancy actions. These actions work exactly the same way as the various sorcery actions: one action for Shadowlands Circle spells, two actions for Labyrinth Circle spells. For complete information about necromancy, and all the better-known spells, see The Books of Sorcery, Vol. II - The Black Treatise.</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Labyrinth Circle Necromancy</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
         <ok>Solars</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Abyssals, page 162</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>4</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>4</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Shadowlands Circle Necromancy</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>This Charm permits the character to take Labyrinth Circle Sorcery actions.</description>
   </charms>
   <charms>
      <name>Void Circle Necromancy</name>
      <creator>White Wolf</creator>
      <allowed>
         <ok>Abyssals</ok>
      </allowed>
      <reference>Manual of Exalted Power: Abyssals, page 162</reference>
      <cost>-</cost>
      <skill>
         <name>Occult</name>
         <value>5</value>
         <primary>true</primary>
      </skill>
      <skill>
         <name>Essence</name>
         <value>5</value>
      </skill>
      <type>Permanent</type>
      <keyword>None</keyword>
      <duration>Instant</duration>
      <prerequest>
         <name>Labyrinth Circle Necromancy</name>
      </prerequest>
      <description>This Charm permits the character to take Void Circle Necromancy actions.</description>
   </charms>
</body>