<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body skill="Skill" type="Spirits" name="Arcanoi">
    <charms>
        <name>First (Ability) Excellency - Essence Overwhelming</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 141</reference>
        <cost>1m per die</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>(Ability)</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive (Step 1 for attacker, Step 2 for defender)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>First (Ability) Excellency - Essence Overwhelming</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm is identical to its Solar counterpart. A spirit cannot use Charms to add more dice to any dice pool than the spirit's Essence. A spirit cannot increase its static values by more than half that amount.
   Spirit Excellencies are related to a specific Virtue depending on the Ability:
• Compassion: Awareness, Craft, Investigation, Linguistics, Lore, Medicine, Survival, War
• Conviction: Bureaucracy, Integrity, Larceny, Performance, Presence, Ride, Sail, Socialize, Stealth
• Valor: Archery, Athletics, Dodge, Martial Arts, Melee, Resistance, Thrown
• Universal: Occult</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Second (Ability) Excellency - Essence Triumphant</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 141</reference>
        <cost>2m per success</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>(Ability)</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive (Step 1 for attacker, Step 2 for defender)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>Second (Ability) Excellency - Essence Triumphant</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm is identical to its Solar counterpart. A spirit cannot use Charms to add more dice to any dice pool than the spirit's Essence. A spirit cannot increase its static values by more than half that amount.
   Spirit Excellencies are related to a specific Virtue depending on the Ability:
• Compassion: Awareness, Craft, Investigation, Linguistics, Lore, Medicine, Survival, War
• Conviction: Bureaucracy, Integrity, Larceny, Performance, Presence, Ride, Sail, Socialize, Stealth
• Valor: Archery, Athletics, Dodge, Martial Arts, Melee, Resistance, Thrown
• Universal: Occult</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Third (Ability) Excellency - Essence Resurgent</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 141</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>(Ability)</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive (Step 4 for attacker, Step 6 for defender)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>Third (Ability) Excellency - Essence Resurgent</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm is identical to its Solar counterpart. A spirit cannot use Charms to add more dice to any dice pool than the spirit's Essence. A spirit cannot increase its static values by more than half that amount.
   Spirit Excellencies are related to a specific Virtue depending on the Ability:
• Compassion: Awareness, Craft, Investigation, Linguistics, Lore, Medicine, Survival, War
• Conviction: Bureaucracy, Integrity, Larceny, Performance, Presence, Ride, Sail, Socialize, Stealth
• Valor: Archery, Athletics, Dodge, Martial Arts, Melee, Resistance, Thrown
• Universal: Occult</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Infinite (Ability) Mastery</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 141</reference>
        <cost>2m+, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>(Ability)</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>Infinite (Ability) Mastery</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>Any (Ability) Excellency</name>
            <trouble>
            <prerequest>
                <name>First (Ability) Excellency - Essence Overwhelming</name>
            </prerequest>
            <prerequest>
                <name>Second (Ability) Excellency - Essence Triumphant</name>
            </prerequest>
            <prerequest>
                <name>Third (Ability) Excellency - Essence Resurgent</name>
            </prerequest>
            </trouble>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm is identical to its Solar counterpart. A spirit cannot use Charms to add more dice to any dice pool than the spirit's Essence. A spirit cannot increase its static values by more than half that amount.
   This Excellency is related to Temperance</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Divine Subordination Of (Ability)</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 142</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>(Ability)</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Spirits with this Charm exercise their divine will to automatically succeed on any check of the Ability in question. When the spirit's player invokes this Charm, she forgoes rolling for a single task and instead the spirit succeeds on that task with a threshold of 0, regardless of the roll's difficulty or external penalties. When associated with a combat Ability used to calculate a Defense Value (Martial Arts, Melee or Dodge), the spirit's player can invoke this Charm to perfectly defend against a single incoming attack, whether the attack can normally be blocked or dodged. Used in this manner, the Charm possesses one of the Four Flaws of Invulnerability (see Exalted, p. 194).
   As with almost all spirit Charms, each spirit with Divine (Ability) Subordination will have unique limitations applied to its invocation (in addition to the Flaw of Invulnerability). Even when All-Encompassing, this Charm suffers one of the Four Flaws of Invulnerability when used for defense.
   This Excellency is related to Temperance</description>
        <errata>
            <todo>replace</todo>
            <date>08-03-2012</date>
            <reference>Exalted 2.5 (Scroll of Errata, page 191)</reference>
            <errText>Employing Divine Subordination of (Ability) as a perfect effect costs 10 motes, 1 Willpower.</errText>
        </errata>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Essence Plethora</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 142</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>A spirit increases its Essence pool by 10 with this Charm. Spirits may take this Charm (Essence) times, and its effects stack.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Hurry Home</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 142</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm dematerializes a spirit and teleports it instantly to a place within the spirit's domain, its sanctum, the nearest gate to Yu-Shan or the point where the spirit entered Creation. A spirit must be dematerialized or be able to dematerialize to use this Charm.
   Hurry Home follows all Relocation guidelines (see p. 156).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Materialize</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 142</reference>
        <cost>Varies</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Varies</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>With this Charm, a god may become material by spending ([Essence + Willpower] x 5) motes. These motes are not committed, and a materialized spirit may respire Essence normally. A material god may dematerialize as a miscellaneous action at no mote cost. Normally, only gods and demons may learn this Charm.
   Elementals, Eclipse Caste Solars, Moonshadow Caste Abyssals and God-Bloods learn a Charm called Dematerialize. With Dematerialize, a naturally material being may become immaterial by spending ([Essence + Willpower] x 5) uncommitted motes. A being under the effect of Dematerialize may become material once again with a miscellaneous action at no mote cost.
       Materialize and its counterpart are exceptions to a number of rules and guidelines about spirit Charms. First, only the most unusual of spirits have restrictions on how they can use these Charms. There's no All-Encompassing Materialize or Dematerialize, because the Charm itself is All-Encompassing in most cases. Second, when an Eclipse or Moonshadow learns Dematerialize, his player calculates the cost in motes from the character's own traits, rather than using a version of the Charm with a mote cost defined by the spiritual tutor's traits.
   The meaning and potential applications of this Charm are highlighted in the "Charm Concept: Material and Immaterial" sidebar below.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Measure The Wind</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 143</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm determines the Essence trait of all living creatures within a number of yards equal to the spirit's Willpower. This Charm also allows for a (Wits + Perception) roll to find hidden creatures within this range, and the difficulty of this roll is reduced by 2. This Charm recognizes what type of being each creature is - Exalt, spirit, ghost, etc. Finally, the Charm detects whether any creature the spirit examines is capable of killing a god permanently, as with Ghost-Eating Technique.
       Measure the Wind follows all Divination guidelines (see p. 148).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Principle Of Motion</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 144</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 6, DV -2)</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>A spirit may invoke this Charm to gain a number of "banked" actions equal to the spirit's Willpower. At any later time, on the spirit's own turn to act, for as long as the spirit retains motes committed to this Charm, the spirit may reflexively use these banked actions to construct a magical flurry following the same guidelines as the Solar Charm Peony Blossom Attack (see Exalted, p. 191). Such a magical flurry contains a number of actions equal to the banked actions the spirit draws forth, plus one. Banked Principle of Motion actions need not be draw forth all at once. Principle of Motion may not be invoked while motes remain committed to a previous activation of Principle of Motion, and may not be invoked using an action in a flurry Principle of Motion provides.
   The magical flurry generated by drawing forth Principle of Motion actions carries a few limitations due to its peculiar nature outside the normal flow of time. This Charm cannot contain Shape Sorcery actions, Shape Necromancy actions, actions requiring long ticks, actions operating on a dramatic timeframe, Extra Action Charms or Combos (though this last limitation applies only to Eclipses and Moonshadows who learn the Charm, as spirits need not use Combos to activate multiple Charms within the same action).
   Note that it takes an action to invoke this Charm, and one who uses the Charm may only draw banked actions on his turn to act, so it's impossible to invoke Principle of Motion and then make a magical flurry immediately - after invoking Principle of Motion to bank actions, the Charm's user must wait until his next action to draw those actions and construct a magical flurry.</description>
        <errata>
            <todo>replace</todo>
            <date>14-11-2010</date>
            <reference>Scroll of Errata, page 151</reference>
            <errText>A flurry produced by withdrawing actions from this Charm cannot contain more than (Essence + 1) total actions. The mote cost of the Charm is committed until the bank is depleted or the spirit releases them, eliminating any banked actions that may be left over.</errText>
        </errata>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Reserve Of Will</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Universal Charms</name>
            <description>Universal Charms aren't tied to Virtues.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 144</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This power allows a spirit to increase its temporary Willpower pool beyond its Willpower trait. Each instance of this Charm grants a spirit an additional temporary Willpower.
   This Charm can be taken no more than (spirit's Essence) times.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Benefaction</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 144</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target receives a one-die bonus to some sort of roll (any or all rolls only in the case of All-Encompassing Benefaction).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>(Element) Dragon's Embrace</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 144</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Elemental</keyword>
        <keyword>Holy</keyword>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Sickness</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit adjusts the target's core Essence balance in favor of one element, Celestial Incarnae or Primordial. The effects are somewhat positive - but ultimately, any such imbalance is unhealthy, even when administered benevolently. As a result, this power can be used as a curse against unwilling targets, in which case it follows Curse guidelines (see p. 165).
       Potential effects include the following:
• Eliminating the normal penalty for having 0 dots in any Ability associated with the element in question
• Removing the mote surcharge from certain elementally aspected Charms
• Removing the penalty associated with working one magical material
• Fooling certain powers that can ascertain elemental associations
• Variously altering Charm effects that have the Holy or elemental descriptor
• Increasing Essence respiration in appropriately aspected areas by one mote per hour, which might thereby allow respiration in places where it wasn't previously possible
   Stranger and more powerful effects are possible, especially when esoteric creatures or other gods are infused. Most gods possess a version of (Element) Dragon's Embrace capable of producing only one of the above effects; some can use two or three.
   For every positive effect granted by this Charm, the target suffers an emotional or mental imbal-ance of some sort. These take the form of Illusion or Emotion effects that occasionally force the target's player to spend one Willpower lest they dramatically manifest. They might influence a character into acting strangely - perhaps out of uncontrollable, fiery rage - or based on incorrect beliefs - perhaps due to wispy, airy hallucinations.Some spirits, especially elementals and servants of the Celestial Incarnae, seem to spring into being with the effects of this Charm as a permanent part of their existence.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Endowment</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 146</reference>
        <cost>Varies, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target gains an immense boon. This Charm can grant dots of traits such as Attributes, Abilities, Willpower, Virtues - even Essence. Endowment can grant the use of Charms. It can even grant physical or metaphysical alterations. Almost any sort of boon is possible, though generally the spirit possess that quality itself. The minimum Essence of this Charm is determined by the granted power, and the mote cost is equal to triple the final minimum Essence. When bestowing trait dots, increase the minimum Essence by two for every dot gifted after the first. Blessing a target beyond her normal potential - for instance, beyond five Attribute dots or one Essence for a mortal - increases the minimum Essence by two more.
   If an Endowment bestows the use of a Charm, then use the minimum Essence of the bestowed Charm (if higher than that of Endowment). If it bestows the effects of a Charm, on the other hand, the duration of the Endowment is limited to the duration of the gifted Charm, and the spirit must pay the cost of the Endowment plus the cost of the bestowed Charm.
   Endowments that grant physical benefits other than Charms or trait dots can be modeled with the "Touch of the Wyld" section on pages 288-290 of Exalted. (Even more such benefits may be found on pp. 144-148 of The Compass of Celestial Directions, Vol. II - The Wyld and on pp. 206-209 of The Manual of Exalted Power - The Lunars). Endowment can add positive qualities or remove negative ones. If the Endowment is about as useful as an affliction or heals a problem as bad as a debility, add one to this Charm's minimum Essence. Blights and deformities raise minimum Essence by two; abominations by three.
       Most spirits have one unique version of this Charm that bestows a combination of effects. If a spirit's Endowment grants dots of various traits, physical changes and Charm effects, use the highest minimum Essence of all of the effects and add one for every additional effect.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Eye Of Inspiration</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 146</reference>
        <cost>15m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target is blessed by one of the spirit's Excellencies, which can add up to the spirit's Essence in dice. These dice always count toward the maximum number of dice the target can add to her pools through Charms.
   The recipient may be allowed to instinctively understand how to draw upon it when she needs it, or the spirit might set conditions in which the Excellency activates (for instance, "When fighting an enemy of my faith"), or the spirit may choose when to use the Excellency itself to assist the recipient.
   A target of this Charm with her own mote pools may fuel the Excellency's activation with her own motes. Otherwise, the spirit must allow her to draw from its own pool.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Signet Of Authority</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 146</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target is marked by the spirit's sigil (though the mark may only be visible to senses that penetrate the immaterial) and can give orders in its name. She's much less likely to be attacked by the god's inferiors, and may spend one Willpower to call upon the Mandate of Subordination (see p. 169) and give an order that such an inferior must follow, as long as it's seen the signet on the target.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch Of Divinity</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <reference>Scroll of the Monk, page 17</reference>
        <cost>3m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Dramatic Action)</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite (see below)</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm enables a spirit to commit three motes of its Essence to a favored mortal. The process can take many forms, such as a light kiss on the brow, a sigil branded on the mortal's back, a chanted rite ending in a drink of strong wine or whatever suits the spirit's fancy. Elemental versions emphasize the spirit's chosen element. Demons favor cruelty, pain and degradation. Nephwracks or other powerful ghosts might place the subject in a bone-strewn coffin. The procedure involved can range from less than a minute to hours.
   Whatever form the Charm takes, the blessed recipient feels the unaccustomed power of Essence flood through her body in an unmistakable, electric surge. All her senses seem sharper, colors look brighter, and she feels transcendent joy - or terror.
   Touch of Divinity grants no measurable benefits beyond enabling its recipient to perceive Essence in use. The spirit can take back its committed Essence whenever it wants. A mortal can use his new sense for Essence to learn how to channel it himself, though. After each month the recipient carries the borrowed Essence, the recipient's player rolls ([highest Mental Attribute] + Martial Arts) at difficulty 3. Once the roll succeeds, the mortal gains his own Essence pool, and the spirit can take back the committed motes. The mortal's permanent Essence hasn't changed (that requires bonus points or experience points to raise), but he has joined the supernatural world. The enlightened mortal character can now learn supernatural martial arts.
   The mortal gains an affinity for whatever divine force empowered her. A mortal empowered by a sacred cavern's elemental, for instance, is aspected to the element earth. A mortal empowered by a demon would possess a demonic aspect, while a ghost's use of this Charm would confer a necromantic aspect. This affinity of Essence does not affect how an enlightened mortal learns or practices supernatural martial arts, but it could become important in other circumstances. (For instance, any Exalt would feel justifiable suspicion of any mortal whose Essence carries a demonic taint).
   Touch of Divinity offers little benefit to people who are already Exalted or otherwise able to use Essence. The spirit simply passes three motes to the recipient. If the recipient has a full Essence pool already, the three motes are wasted.</description>
        <errata>
            <todo>replace</todo>
            <date>2007</date>
            <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 146</reference>
            <cost>3m+, 1wp</cost>
            <type>Simple</type>
            <duration>One scene</duration>
            <description>This Charm can be a gift of motes, Willpower points or some other temporary spiritual renewal. If motes are transferred, then they're given on a one-for-one basis. Temporary Willpower costs three motes of Essence and one of the spirit's own temporary Willpower per point. More potent examples include nourishment or Virtue channels, which cost more than motes or Willpower. Spirits cannot spend more motes per use of this Charm than their (Essence x 3).
       If the spirit consents, the target may receive this boon permanently; the spirit may also withdraw it at any time before the Charm ends. These blessings are usually much more specific and interesting than motes or Willpower. Recipients have been known to use the divine boon as a guide to awaken their own Essence, uncover esoteric truths buried deep within themselves, relive memories lost to the Ages and so on.</description>
        </errata>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch Of Eternity</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 147</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target's body and soul are reinforced with the resilience of immortality. The effects vary, but examples include the following:
• Soak lethal damage with half Stamina, as do Essence wielders
• Rapidly stop bleeding as an Exalt does
• Resist poison and disease as an Exalt does
• Heal as fully and rapidly as an Exalt does
• Shrug off enchantments and curses as an Exalt does
• Half aging speed (does not stack with other uses of this Charm)
       Powerful gods can imbue recipients with more powerful and creative effects. Some can even enhance the Exalted, but this blessing cannot generally bestow powers the spirit itself doesn't possess.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch Of Grace</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Blessings - Gifts From The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits use blessings to aid their allies in battle, but more importantly, blessings often ensure the loyalty and effective service of a spirit's messengers, followers and lieutenants.
   All recipients of a blessing must be willing. If the target (or targets) possess Essence 1, the motes the spirit spends to power the blessing Charm are uncommitted, and the spirit may do so from any distance (unless the spirit possesses a version of the Charm that must be delivered through physical contact or presence), provided she has an arcane link to the target (most commonly prayer; see pp. 168-169). If a target possesses Essence 2+, the spirit must be in his presence in some fashion and commit the motes to bless the target.
   Some spirits can issue blessings that deactivate under certain conditions. Blessings from similar sources and with similar purposes don't stack their effects.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 147</reference>
        <cost>3m+, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Touch of Grace allows a spirit to pour its own ephemeral substance into cracks and wounds, mending them. Spirits might use the Charm to fix broken parts of their domain, to perform miraculous healings or perhaps to relieve themselves of minor damage.
   For every three motes a spirit spends powering this Charm, the target removes one health level of damage (one mote per level, if the damage is bashing). Recipients may even remain healed after the duration of the Charm has expired, if the spirit wishes.
   This considerable power has weaknesses. Wounds that are too deep cannot be healed: a spirit may spend no more motes per usage than its ([lower of Essence or Compassion] x 3), and if the spirit can't heal the target completely with a single use of Touch of Grace, the Charm has no effect. Also, damage of a supernatural nature, including all aggravated damage, can be healed only until the spirit uncommits the motes fueling the Charm - whereupon it returns.
   Touch of Grace can cure Crippling, Poison or Sickness effects. To determine the mote cost, each counts as a number of lethal health levels equal to a Poison's Toxicity, a Sickness's Untreated Morbidity or a Crippling effect's relative seriousness, as decided by the Storyteller on a scale of 1 to 5. Unusually powerful effects may count as up to 10. Supernatural effects, such as magical wounds, also return when the duration ends.
   Touch of Grace has no effect on artifacts or on things that are in stark opposition to the spirit's nature. For example, undead or demons usually cannot benefit from this Charm if it's used by a god of the Celestial Hierarchy, and a water elemental may not understand how to heal a creature made of fire.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Amethyst Awareness</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 148</reference>
        <cost>6</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive (Step 1)</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>All-Encompassing Sorcerer's Sight</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm provides the benefits of All-Encompassing Sorcerer's Sight (see Exalted, p. 222).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Foretell The Future</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 148</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit spends one entire scene in prayer formulating a personal passkey into the Bureau of Destiny's archive of fates. At the scene's end, the spirit dreams her way through the archives, researching her domain. She has access only to materials associated by the Bureau with her domain. The Bureau of Destiny has the right to restrict access to this information to beings who possess a certain Essence score, but a spirit may spend one Willpower to perform a priority override (requiring a Compassion roll and then adding the successes to the spirit's effective Essence score). The Bureau is alerted to priority overrides and who knows what else that goes on in its dream archives.
   With this Charm, the spirit has limited access to the future. If the Bureau of Destiny cannot determine what will happen, neither then can the spirit. If a destiny is in flux, the spirit receives incomplete prophecies - the best Heaven can reasonably determine.
   This Charm is an exception to the usual prohibition against Divinations crossing realms of existence.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Hand Of Destiny</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 148</reference>
        <cost>20m, 2wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Using Hand of Destiny, a spirit marks a certain part of its domain for personal attention. The spirit personally decides what must happen, and personally accomplishes that end. Subordinate spirits governing affected domains immediately become aware of their superior's floating decree and level of personal involvement; thus, those spirits also actively work toward the end the Charm is shaping.
   By using this Charm, the spirit sets itself upon a path that leads to the spirit's goal. The spirit becomes the Hand of Destiny: an instrument of its own decision to interfere with Creation. The spirit has a perfect, unconscious instinct for everything that brings it closer to success, and often takes great steps toward its larger goal without even realizing its actions were relevant till later.
   This Charm is essentially a managerial priority override - it brings the spirit into conflict with the way things will work out "naturally". As a result, spirits using this Charm without permission from the Bureau of Destiny risk that Bureau's wrath.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Intrusion-Sensing Method</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit defines a potential change within its domain and commits the requisite motes. If that event occurs, roll the spirit's (Perception + Awareness), adding (Compassion) automatic successes. This constitutes a check to notice that change as though the spirit were present at the event's location.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Melodious Diagnostic Report</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>15m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit focuses on a problem affecting her do-main and issues notice of impending analysis. By the end of the scene, her being resonates with the wise prayers of every aspect of Creation that owes fealty to the spirit. Unless the problem is masked by magic backed by a higher Essence score than the spirit's, the spirit will determine the problem's source, and may then roll (Intelligence + Compassion) to determine how to fix it. Problems well beyond the spirit's normal scope of operations may impose an external penalty to this roll. For instance, if the issue is a Essence 9 Lunar working against the spirit's domain, then the spirit will likely take a large penalty to the spirit's (Intelligence + Compassion) roll - it's really hard to find a solution to a Essence 9 Lunar. The number of threshold successes determines the wisdom of the spirit's conclusions, and subsequent mental rolls made to deal with the problem receive bonus dice equal to those successes.
   Subordinate spirits involved in the diagnostic report must pray to issue their decisions, and any such spirit with an Essence score 1 less than the user may attempt to upset the process, creating an external penalty equal to its ([Charisma + Performance] / 2). A greater number of rebellious smaller spirits might also upset this Charm.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Memory Mirror</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit finds what it seeks in the target's mind. The spirit attempts to read her per Reading Motivation (see Exalted, p. 131), but actually reads something besides Intimacies and Motivation, such as a memory. Unless the target's Essence exceeds the spirit's, the Reading Motivation check receives (Compassion) automatic successes.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Natural Prognostication</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit's words and actions casually reveal fate's plans. This Charm activates automatically when the spirit encounters a character or region for which Heaven has a weighty plan. The Charm reveals the preplanned fates of those with the Destiny Background (see Scroll of the Monk, p. 151), though the Charm cannot determine the Background's strength. Natural Prognostication also senses the effects of ascending or descending destinies caused by Sidereal astrology.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Sense Domain</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>5m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>When the spirit invokes this Charm, the spirit's player makes a single Awareness roll pertinent to the spirit's domain's status or interior (if the domain is a location). The Charm adds (Compassion) automatic successes to the roll, and the spirit may count its priests' senses as part of its domain. The spirit can explicitly notice anything within its domain that the Storyteller deems noticeable - even things beyond the reach of its normal senses.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Tracking</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divinations - Eyes Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits can perceive many things beyond mortal ken.
   Divinations are an exception to the normal rule for retries; similar Divinations can interfere with each other. A Divination that would glean data contradicting another Divination the spirit has made within the past month won't yield information contradicting the earlier Divination, and might be influenced into giving false predictions. As a result, diviner-spirits prefer to ritually invoke their foresight no more often than once a month.
   Divinations can see only into the sanctums of willing gods, and only the most powerful divination can see into other realms of existence.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 149</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit tracks something or someone to which the spirit has committed Essence, whether by a blessing, a curse or any Charm requiring committed motes. The spirit instinctively knows the target's distance from the spirit, as well as in what direction the target lies. Any spirit with this Charm may also commit a mote to a target for an indefinite period with a touch and a successful (Essence + Compassion) check; unwilling targets apply an external penalty to this roll equal to their Essence. Removing this "tag" usually requires specialized thaumaturgy or sorcery, though cutting the tag out occasionally works. This tag is an arcane link to the spirit, so cautious spirits use the tag sparingly.
   If the target of this Charm has access to supernatural stealth, the spirit's player rolls (Essence + Awareness), adding (Compassion) successes, and the target's player rolls (Essence + Stealth), adding dice or successes from other sources. The power associated with the winning roll overrides the power associated with the losing roll. The target's player may invoke Excellencies to increase the dice pool for this roll even if the target character is unaware she's being tracked.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Call</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Sendings - Voices Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits send dreams to their worshipers and visions to their priests, and often manipulate humanity from a distance. A spirit can use a Sending on a target within Creation from within the spirit's own sanctum, but Sending can only enter the sanctum of a willing spirit and cannot otherwise cross between realms of existence. A spirit doesn't necessarily know if its Sending failed to reach the target.
   Sendings may reach material targets, even if the spirit itself is immaterial.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 150</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit sends (Compassion) simple ideas to any or all creatures within range, but only those who share a particular quality with the spirit will hear the message. Many spirits and demons use this Charm to communicate with others of their kind.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Dreamscape</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Sendings - Voices Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits send dreams to their worshipers and visions to their priests, and often manipulate humanity from a distance. A spirit can use a Sending on a target within Creation from within the spirit's own sanctum, but Sending can only enter the sanctum of a willing spirit and cannot otherwise cross between realms of existence. A spirit doesn't necessarily know if its Sending failed to reach the target.
   Sendings may reach material targets, even if the spirit itself is immaterial.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 150</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <duration>Instant Or Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target receives a dream of the spirit's design. Sleepers can enter only one such dreamscape per period of sleep. If more than one spirit seeks to place a target within a dreamscape during the same period of sleep, the highest-Essence spirit's dream takes precedence. In case of ties, the target enters the dreamscape sent first. A spirit may commit the motes for this Charm, specifying that it activates as soon as the target is willing to receive the dream or falls asleep, but won't necessarily know when that happens. Most spirits with this Charm may send dreams only to mortals the spirits can see, though they may do so while immaterial. Spirits with Essence 6+ may send dreams (Essence x Compassion x 100) miles.
   From within the dream, the target may receive any message of any length - through this message, the spirit may deliver a social attack that gains twice the normal benefit from using the target's Intimacies, Virtues or Motivations against him, up to a maximum bonus equal to the spirit's Compassion. If the spirit is activating this Charm while the target sleeps, the spirit may enter the dream and communicate with her in real time, in which case the spirit may deliver one social attack at the above bonus or hold a regular conversation, including the possibility of participating in regular social combat where the spirit's as vulnerable to the dreamer as the dreamer is to it. The dream message may also constitute up to a full day's worth of training. Finally, the dream can simply be a nightmare, designed to prevent the target from regaining Willpower upon waking.
   For one Willpower, spirits with an Essence score greater than the target's Dodge Mental Defense Value can force conscious targets into a dream, which lasts but a moment, though its effects may be profound. Targets may lower their Dodge Mental Defense Value voluntarily should they wish to receive such a dream.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Impromptu Messenger</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Sendings - Voices Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits send dreams to their worshipers and visions to their priests, and often manipulate humanity from a distance. A spirit can use a Sending on a target within Creation from within the spirit's own sanctum, but Sending can only enter the sanctum of a willing spirit and cannot otherwise cross between realms of existence. A spirit doesn't necessarily know if its Sending failed to reach the target.
   Sendings may reach material targets, even if the spirit itself is immaterial.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 151</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit usurps control of a mortal's voice or speaks through an inanimate object if the object has a feature that could function as a mouth. Assuming they share a common language, the spirit can hear and speak to anyone near its vector.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Worldly Illusion</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Sendings - Voices Of The Gods (Compassion)</name>
            <description>Spirits send dreams to their worshipers and visions to their priests, and often manipulate humanity from a distance. A spirit can use a Sending on a target within Creation from within the spirit's own sanctum, but Sending can only enter the sanctum of a willing spirit and cannot otherwise cross between realms of existence. A spirit doesn't necessarily know if its Sending failed to reach the target.
   Sendings may reach material targets, even if the spirit itself is immaterial.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 151</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit uses its understanding of immortality to place itself and its targets outside of time. While this Essence is committed, the spirit (or another of its Send-ings) and a number of targets up to the spirit's Essence depart the normal flow of time and enter into a mass dream. This effect is usually consensual, but targets with a Dodge Mental Defense Value greater than the spirit's (Essence + Compassion) may choose to be unaffected. One spirit may cause the world to appear to freeze in place. Another may appear to transport itself and its targets to a far away location or to a location the spirit imagines. There, the spirit and its targets may wage social combat between the blows of a sword or strategize in the midst of a battle. Once the committed Essence is released, all the participants return to exactly where they were just before this Charm was used.
   What happens in the dream is purely social. No changes whatsoever last beyond the end of the conversation save the effects of social combat, with the special exception of Compassion Charms invoked during that "time".
   A player who wants her character to leave the dream world may spend three Willpower to do so.
   This Charm may be used a number of times per scene equal to the spirit's Compassion.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Affinity (Element) Control</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 151</reference>
        <cost>6m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Elemental</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Stackable</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit has considerable control over a particular element. The spirit may manipulate (Essence) barrels worth of that element equal within (Essence x 10) yards. Every action, each barrel can be used to one of a number of effects.
• Elemental Corruption/Purification - The spirit makes its element poisonous, changing sand into toxic salt, befouling waters, etc. The Damage is 1L/minute and the Toxicity is 1. Every additional barrel committed to the poison adds 1 to the damage and 1 to the Toxicity. This poison is only dangerous if internalized. Every barrel contains 100 doses of this poison. With the purifica-tion effect, the spirit may cleanse its element, removing poisonous qualities. The spirit may also cleanse its element of diseases with Virulence less than the spirit's Essence. These effects are permanent.
• Elemental Damage - Every barrel adds 1 to the damage of the spirit's attacks.
• Elemental Hazard - The spirit creates an environmental hazard from its element. This hazard has a damage of 1L/minute and a Trauma of 1L. Every additional barrel committed to the hazard adds 1 to the damage and Trauma. Barrels of the element committed to an already existing hazard enhance it in the same way or add the L tag to the hazard's trauma. This effect   152 supersedes the effects of Elemental Expression (see p. 170) and cannot be combined with hazards created or enhanced by other spirits.
• Elemental Material - The spirit may manipulate its element as though it were a much more useful material. The spirit's Craft score for this is limited to its Conviction, but it requires no tools, and what would take scenes takes only actions. If the material is solid, then it remains after the Charm expires.
• Elemental Resistance - Every barrel adds 1 to the character's bashing, lethal and aggravated soak values, or triple that amount against damage from the same element. This soak counts as armor.
• Elemental Weapon - The spirit may launch attacks with its element, rolling (Wits + Conviction) to hit. This attack has Speed 5, Accuracy +1, base Damage 3B or 3L and a Rate of 1. Every additional barrel committed to an attack adds 1 to the Accuracy and Rate and 3 to the damage. Some spirits may make special attacks with the elements that they control, such as grapples or disarms, and other can even use their element to make ranged Athletics actions.
   Not every spirit can perform every function of the Charm.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Calculated Order Of Immediate Action</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 152</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Variable</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>With this power, the spirit outright creates or destroys an instance of its domain within (Essence x 10) yards. The spirit's authority cuts the red tape that delays projects, making complicated and difficult feats as quick as stamping a form. As long as the spirit has the necessary power, Abilities and raw materials to mundanely create or destroy the spirit's target, this Charm makes it happen within a matter of seconds. The first moments of Calculated Order of Immediate Action begin the process; this is Power Level 0 (see chart, below). This Charm can then be reinvoked, with each new use increasing Power Level by one until the spirit is finished. At that point, the Divine Work is complete. If interrupted, the process must be entirely restarted. Objects created with this Charm are born with weak least gods, making them particularly vulnerable to ownership and Inhabitings.
   This Charm's Essence minimum increases by the desired Power Level - a god with Essence 2 can invoke only Power Level 0 effects, and a god must be Essence 7 to invoke effects of Power Level 5.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Chrysalis Of Preservation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 152</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit invests some of its immortal, intangible self in something, making that thing immune to age and anything that can't affect the immaterial. Against things that affect dematerialized creatures, this Chrysalis has a Hardness equal to the spirit's (Essence x Conviction). However, crystallized things can't change, move, be used, improve or do anything but be perceived. Only creatures with Charms that can affect things even more intangible than the immaterial - for instance, Creation of Perfection (below) - can touch it.
   Anything at all can be thus crystallized. Concepts lose a little potential, but gain a pseudo-material form holding part of their power. People and artifacts can be crystallized, but only by Essence 6+ spirits; Exalted and their Essences can't be crystallized by any being of less than Essence 9. However, the spirit may not surround a being of Essence 2+ with a Chrysalis of Preservation without the target's consent. Since crystallizing things can weaken their spirits, gaining consent can be tricky. Furthermore, only spirits with an Essence equal to or greater than the target's Essence or the Essence of the target's spirit can crystallize a thing. As most things only have least gods, this is seldom a concern when creating a chrysalis around an object.
       Releasing this Charm's motes decrystallizes the thing, as does inflicting any damage upon it at all. A spirit whose Essence or Conviction is higher than the Conviction of the crystallizing spirit might itself be able to use this Charm to end a chrysalis.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Creation Of Perfection</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 153</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit becomes tangible to everything - material, immaterial, barely substantial or wildly conceptual, though concepts at least need a representation for the spirit to touch. A spirit might use this Charm to work Fate through the Loom of Fate, or to prune a concept wrapped within a Chrysalis of Preservation (see above). This uses the normal Craft rules. Conviction limits the spirit's Craft score, but the spirit can call upon the Excellencies.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Divine Decree</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 153</reference>
        <cost>Varies</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit delivers a powerful order that is unhesi-tatingly enforced by subordinates who control lesser aspects of the spirit's domain. The relative power of the spirit's invocation is determined by the Decree's Power Level. A Power Level 1 decree might be: "This statue of me shall stay spotless", at which point the idol will never again need polishing. A Power Level 3 decree might be: "The ocean shall swallow you and your children", in which case it would be prudent for the target to avoid the sea. A Power Level 5 decree might be: "The Imperial City offers no quarter to Anathema", in which case all doors might close and lock when any Celestial Exalt approaches, and citizens would normally show distaste and distrust toward them.
   Each Divine Decree has one Power Level for every invested 10 motes and one Willpower. Using this Charm involves harassing and commanding spirits with all Essence scores equal to or less than the Power Level, so using high levels runs a serious risk of angering other powerful bureaucrats, who can spend Willpower to resist this Charm as they would the Mandate of Subordination. In any case, a spirit can't manifest a greater Power Level than its (Essence - 1). The exact effects of this Charm are unpredictable, but as a quick rule, attempts to contradict the decree always require a roll, to which an external penalty equal to the Power Level is applied.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Domain Manipulation Scenario</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 154</reference>
        <cost>6m or 12m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2; Type: Simple</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>
        </type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>For six motes, the spirit commands its domain to do something normal, or "naturally" calls its domain into existence. The spirit can slow or stop its domain's natural processes, but only in a relatively plausible way. This Charm has a range of (Essence x 10) yards. The god of a volcano could make his volcano erupt if he's inside it; a love goddess could make two nearby people who are actually right for each other fall in love.
   Essence 3+ spirits might spend 12 motes and one Willpower to guide their domains in temporary, moderately powerful ways. A spirit might cause its domain to do almost anything that isn't extremely rapid or outside its nature: a disease spirit could induce plague in an unexpected area - but not a magically sterilized one; a river spirit could cause its river to dry up, overflow its banks or even alter its course - but couldn't make it fly. A city father might decide that all shops are closed for the day, but couldn't move the place or make it invisible. This Charm's threats are never so powerful that a person with a Defense Value (or Mental Defense Value, when appropriate) greater than the spirit's Conviction couldn't best them.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Weather Control</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Divine Works - Hands Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Many spirits can affect their domains without personal interaction - examples include raising and lowering mountains, erupting volcanoes and deciding the bounty of the harvest.
   Spirits complete Divine Works by calling upon their domains, so these Charms function at limited capacity - if at all - when a spirit is outside its station. Gods outside Creation, demons outside Malfeas and elementals in places where their elements cannot exist (for instance, a wood elemental in a howling inferno) count their Essence scores as being 3 lower when invoking Divine Works.
   Some of these Charms are Shaping powers. They casually alter extras' minds and could change Creation on almost any level. However, Divine Works cannot reshape anyone of Essence 2+, or any artifact, in any dramatic fashion. The Charm might still affect such targets - it just can't use them to complete its effect: a Celestial Exalt might be affected by a Divine Decree that the Imperial City is inhospitable to Anathema, but the Decree can't force her to make it inhospitable to Anathema.
   Divine Works can only be performed while the spirit is material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 154</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>(Essence) hours</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit manipulates nearby weather in a semi-natural way. For the first scene, the spirit "mildly" affects the weather within a one-mile radius. The next scene, the spirit intensifies the weather within this zone by one level of severity (see chart), creating a "mild" zone around that for another mile. This continues till the weather reaches its maximum radius: one mile per Essence dot. The spirit need not intensify the weather to expand its radius.
   Excellent thaumaturgy or a spirit with greater Essence and Weather Control could both counteract this Charm. Spirits who commonly regulate an area's weather have the appreciation of Heaven's Celestial Monitors of the Seasons and Weather. Others, without such permission, might attract the Bureau's ire.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Form Reduction Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Eidola - Forms Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits can take many shapes and can even reform their domains to protect them.
   Eidola can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 154</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit compacts its substance into a smaller shape; this shape doesn't usually have traits or significantly useful qualities that the spirit could not otherwise call upon -it thus becomes the lesser creature in all respects, and could be a lower-Essence spirit, mortal, animal or any other living thing.
   This Charm can't emulate specific creatures; it mimics certain types of creatures or creates new ones. Unlike other Eidola, Form Reduction Technique actually remakes the spirit in every way that matters. No senses, spiritual or otherwise, will perceive the spirit as anything but what it's become. This isn't an Illusion effect. Short of extrapolation based on considerable knowledge of a given spirit - its exact speech patterns, for instance - there's no way anyone can figure out the deception. Picking up those subtle cues requires a successful (Perception + Occult) roll, suffering an external penalty of the spirit's (Essence + Occult + Conviction).
   If the spirit becomes a creature with a smaller Essence pool than the spirit's own, the extra motes go Elsewhere, and the spirit regains them upon resuming its normal form. This Charm shapes no equipment save the being's divine panoply.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Host Of Spirits</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Eidola - Forms Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits can take many shapes and can even reform their domains to protect them.
   Eidola can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 155</reference>
        <cost>3m per copy</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>One scene or indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit animates a piece of itself into its full shape. Weak spirits create doppelgangers to fool or outnumber foes; powerful ones also create units of followers or avatars to send out into the world.
       (Conviction) copies can be formed per action, to a maximum of (Essence x Conviction) at any one time, and each costs the spirit three committed motes. These doppelgangers possess all of the spirit's traits and other qualities, but two fewer dots of each Attribute save Appearance (Minimum 0), only the illusion of equipment, no Charms, motes of Essence or temporary Willpower, and only a single -0 health level. Each member of the Host has an Essence three less than the spirit's (minimum 1). Such copies last until the end of the scene under the perfect mental command of the spirit.
   With a touch, copies can be invested with motes or temporary Willpower by the true spirit, but never recover them once they're spent or lost. If a copy meets the prerequisites, it can also be imbued with the spirit's Charms, but the original will lose access to those Charms as long as the doppelganger persists. Charms return to the spirit upon a copy's destruction, but not motes or Willpower.
   Essence 3+ spirits may spend one Willpower to allow another character to don one of the spirit's copy bodies. Any basically humanoid creature smaller than the spirit may enter into a Host copy, riding it until she chooses to leave or the spirit releases the three committed motes. While inside, the inner creature sees as the copy would see, with the spirit's senses. The inner creature may not, however, use any of her own Charms without disrupting the power, and all of her Physical Attributes and Abilities are considered those of the doppelganger, as well as its Essence score.
   Wearing a copy constitutes a perfect disguise, per the Charm Flawless Mirror (see Exalted, p. 228); if the character suffers any damage while wearing a Host copy, however, she's exposed.
   The spirit need not invoke a Host that looks exactly like it, but it will need other Charms such as Shapechange if the spirit wishes to alter forms more than a little. If the spirit decides its doppelgangers are exact, then onlookers seeking the original must succeed at a (Perception + [Awareness or Occult]) check with an external penalty of (spirit's Conviction) to do so.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Mirror Of The Infinite Wardrobe</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Eidola - Forms Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits can take many shapes and can even reform their domains to protect them.
   Eidola can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 155</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit pisguises itself as something it can perceive. Creatures with a Dodge Mental Defense Value greater than the spirit's (Essence + Conviction) can pierce the Eidola just by spending one Willpower, and if the illusion is pointed out, anyone may spend one Willpower to spot it. Otherwise, the Mirror of the Infinite Wardrobe requires either Willpower or successes on a (Perception + Occult) roll equal to the spirit's Conviction to overcome the unnatural mental influence.
       Most spirits have one alternate form, and may carry a likeness of that shape. Powerful ones are more flexible; one demon is known for using Memory Mirror (see p. 149) to retrieve the memory of the demon's victims' lovers, then matching those loved ones' forms.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Paper Tiger Arrangement</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Eidola - Forms Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits can take many shapes and can even reform their domains to protect them.
   Eidola can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 155</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>/indefinite
    The spirit creates an illusion surrounding everything within (Essence x 10) yards. If Paper Tiger Arrangement is used only to make something appear as part of the spirit's domain or make a part of the spirit's domain seem to not be, the duration is indefinite. Otherwise, the illusion lasts for a scene, but may be instructed to act in a certain fashion with a Willpower. With a successful Conviction roll, the instructions may be changed by the spirit. Failure means the paper tiger becomes confused, frays and quickly disintegrates.
   Anyone whose Dodge Mental Defense Value exceeds the spirit's (Essence + Conviction) recognizes the illusion. Others who are suspicious may spend three Willpower to disbelieve; if the illusion's pointed out, the recognition costs only one Willpower.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shapechange</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Eidola - Forms Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits can take many shapes and can even reform their domains to protect them.
   Eidola can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 155</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit can alter its physical form. Most spirits of a certain type possess unique alternate forms that they can assume. These spirits generally take on some minor useful physical characteristics of the new form, such as attack modes or different Physical Attributes. These changes don't usually exceed the effects of 1 or 2 Essence spirit Charms. Other spirits are able to assume nearly any shape, and these spirits usually have severe limitations to the powers of those forms that the spirits can assume or suffer from restrictions while in those forms. Almost all shapechanged forms are easily identifiable as the spirit in a new body - those spirits whose Shapechange Charm is useful as a disguise gain a number of automatic successes on their disguise rolls equal to their Conviction. Spirits who possess powerful alternate forms usually have the powerful form as their true form and use Form Reduction Technique (see pp. 154-155) to assume a weaker form.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Banish</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 156</reference>
        <cost>12m 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit purifies its domain of an unwanted element, forcing the target through a portal (see p. 157) out of the spirit's domain or sanctum. Banish may not cross the boundaries of realms of existence save to force the target out of a sanctum, and the spirit has no control over where she goes beyond "away". The portal never deposits the target more than the spirit's (Essence x Conviction x 5) miles away, and always on safe ground. The player of an unwilling target rolls (Stamina + Integrity) to resist, with an external penalty of the god's ([Essence + Conviction] / 2); success protects the character against this Charm for a scene.
   Spirits might also banish instances of their domain from their presence.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Capture</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 156</reference>
        <cost>16m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit opens a portal (see p. 157) and drags the target into a specific place within its domain or sanctum. Capture can pull a target from Creation into a sanctum, but cannot otherwise cross realms of existence. The Charm always deposits targets to the same place. An unwilling target rolls (Stamina + Integrity) to resist, suffering an external penalty of the spirit's ([Essence + Conviction] / 2); success protects her for a scene.
   Spirits might also capture instances of their domains.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Emergency Prayer Relocation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 156</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Variable</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>When a spirit receives a prayer, the spirit may invoke Emergency Prayer Relocation to travel to the petitioner in less than a scene, no matter how far away the prayer is. The actual time taken depends on the target's distance from the spirit - generally one tick per 100 miles.
   Because the spirit's departure is so hasty, the spirit cannot take its entire Essence along. When the spirit arrives, its Essence score is limited to the number of threshold successes the target scored on her prayer roll, and it cannot use Charms with Essence minimums greater than the new Essence score. Furthermore, the spirit cannot remain divided. After taking (Conviction) actions (or up to [Conviction x 6] minutes if it engages only in behavior with no mechanical effect, such as conversing without using social combat), the spirit returns whence it came. The spirit is aware of the strength of the target's prayer and must decide whether such a hasty move is worth the risk.
   The spirit finds dividing its Essence arduous. Every time a spirit uses this Charm in a single scene after the first, the spirit suffers one level of unsoakable aggravated damage.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Landscape Travel</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 157</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>For every two dots of Essence the spirit possesses, it grants itself one of three bonuses:
• One die to all Dexterity rolls associated with a particular form of movement, to a maximum of the spirit's Conviction.
• Double the speed of a particular form of movement.
• Grants itself a new form of movement, just as fast as it would be on land.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Loom Stride</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 157</reference>
        <cost>4m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit replaces its normal Move action with a special Move action that doesn't require it to cross space. This Charm must be invoked on a tick on which the spirit acts. The spirit focuses on a point within (Essence x Conviction) yards, and its player rolls (Wits + Conviction), taking into account vision and cover-based penalties as though the spirit were making a ranged attack. With a successful roll, the spirit instantaneously moves up to (Essence x Conviction) yards. The spirit cannot dash or reflexively move until its next action. Successes on this roll constitute successes on a roll for the spirit to reestablish surprise, which is resisted normally.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Portal</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 157</reference>
        <cost>8m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit summons a door to its sanctum or domain, which appears within (Essence x Conviction) yards of the spirit and lasts up to a scene. The spirit may only use this Charm within (Essence x Conviction x 5) miles of the destination. Characters cannot be moved through a portal against their will (with the exception of portals created through the Banish Charm, see p. 156).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Storm-Shuttle Passport</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Relocations - Movements Of The Gods (Conviction)</name>
            <description>Spirits soar on wings of light and travel Creation as natural forces, sometimes flashing across vast distances in the blink of an eye.
       Relocations can target anything the spirit can perceive within (Essence x Conviction) yards.
   When these Charms involve moving targets to or from a domain, that function of the Charm can only be used by spirits with physical domains. Spirits who wish to banish foes from an abstract domain, or drag them into it, will need to use other methods - a war god cannot end a war simply by expelling all the soldiers fighting it from "war" or by Banishing the war itself. Any spirit whose domain is affected by a Relocation may prevent the Charm's use with nothing but a moment's concentration, but only if its Essence is higher than the spirit using the Relocation, and only if it knows the Relocation is occurring. Some spirits set Intrusion-Sensing Method (see p. 149) to watch for Relocations.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 157</reference>
        <cost>8m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>(10 - Conviction) ticks</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Spirits traveling long distances on official business often rely on storm travel. While a cloud is overhead, the spirit calls down a bolt of lightning that takes the spirit into the cloud; when the cloud reaches the god's destination, the spirit returns to Creation riding the lightning. The spirit must refrain from moving for the Charm's duration. Using this Charm places a certain amount of control - and, therefore, trust - in the hands of the Bureau of Seasons.
   Some spirits with Storm-Shuttle Passport learn thaumaturgy that allows them to summon storms and command their movement.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Geas</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 157</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Crippling</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One month</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit makes a normal social attack to persuade the target to do something; if the attack is successful, the target may still spend Willpower to shrug off the Mental Influence, but her soul cannot. Every day the target doesn't spend working toward the spirit's stated end, she suffers a Crippling effect. (For many spirits, including most Celestial censors, this drains the target of one Willpower and one bashing health level). The losses can't be recovered while the target isn't working toward her geas, and only begin coming back a day after she starts. "Working toward her goal" means the character spends more effort than she is used to spending, even on important endeavors, to pursue the geas. She can only stop to eat, sleep or rest for a few hours a day. The target must sacrifice one Willpower and one bashing health level to take any action that significantly distances her from the geas, and she won't recover that damage on that day. At the end of the month, if the target hasn't done her duty, she suffers as if she missed (spirit's Essence) days.
   Spirits choose geasa carefully; the wording must be very simple to work at all, and clever targets have twisted geasa in the past. Targets can't be geased to perform deeds that they couldn't reasonably complete within the month. Social attacks that are unacceptable orders will also fail unless the spirit can make a target accept unacceptable orders.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Harrow The Mind</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 158</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Crippling</keyword>
        <keyword>Illusion</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit convinces the target that something is true, supplementing a (Manipulation + Presence) attack, adding (Temperance) successes. If this social attack is successful, the target finds the impossible possible, then probable, then certain: she's forced to believe the spirit. She sees things the spirit says are there, feels what the spirit says she feels; she may explicitly act on this information however she wishes, but shw cannot doubt that it's true. Spending one Willpower allows her to disbelieve the illusion for a single action; once the target has spent as many points of Willpower as the spirit's Essence, she's overcome the Charm's effects completely.
   A spirit with Essence 4+ may spend a point of Willpower when invoking this Charm to make its effect Crippling. The illusion persists, in a more manageable form, forcing the target to spend one Willpower each day and during any scene in which the illusion is in any way reinforced to avoid acknowledging the illusion as reality. The effect fades entirely only after the target has successfully resisted the illusion for a number of days equal to the spirit's Essence.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Hoodwink</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 158</reference>
        <cost>Varies</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>With a thousand tricks, the spirit overloads the target's mind. The spirit spends as many motes as it wants. It then counts (motes spent) successes on a special social attack, which can only be made during the tick that an opponent acts, and can only be defended against by the target's Dodge Mental Defense Value. If the spirit is successful, the target suffers a (spirit's Essence) internal penalty to all actions that tick. On a threshold of 5, the target becomes Inactive; at 7, the target forgets where he is and what he was doing, and cannot recall anything about the past scene. This most potent effect usually fades after the target takes (spirit's Essence) actions, but mortals must spend one Willpower before they can begin to recover at all. Finally, until the target's next action, he must make a (Perception + Awareness) roll with a difficulty equal to the threshold to perceive any of the spirit's attacks against him.
   The spirit gains one bonus success if this Charm is used within a social timeframe, and another if the target is taking any actions that don't focus on the spirit specifically. Because Hoodwink is only tiny tricks, the target may spend one Willpower to double his Mental Defense Value against this attack.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Mind-Knife Sacrament</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 159</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <keyword>Training</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Mind-Knife Sacrament reshapes the target's mind. This Charm works only if the spirit is able to repeatedly and freely touch the target during the social action, which requires either restraining the target, or trust. The spirit issues a social attack using ([Charisma or Manipulation] + Temperance), which only the target's Dodge Mental Defense Value may defend against. Successes may seal off or bestow Abilities, Virtues, Intimacies or memories, or bestow priesthood. Sealed traits cannot be used as prerequisites for Charms, and characters who lack the prerequisites for their Charms lose access to those powers.
• Ability dots may not be raised by more than 1, and may not be caused to exceed the spirit's own. They can be reduced to as low as 0. Ability dots require three successes per dot to add or remove.
• Virtue dots also require three successes per dot to add or remove, but the spirit's own Virtues are not a limitation.
• Intimacies cost one success per scene's worth of building or eroding the Intimacy, and the spirit must possess the Intimacy, or a similar one, to bestow it.
• Memories cost one success per scene's worth of memory. Removing elements from larger sections of time requires five successes. Rewriting life-long memories requires 10 successes.
• Priesthood costs five successes.Raising a target's traits puts the target into experience debt per normal for training effects.
       Large-scale revisions to a target's mind are possible because repeated uses of this Charm are cumulative; however, every success applied to the target saps one Willpower from the target, or deals one unsoakable aggravated level of damage if the target runs out of Willpower. When this Charm is used to lower traits, the effects of this Charm are temporary. Every time the target dreams, and every time she is placed in a new situation in which her old mind has an opportunity to resurface, such as a warrior who has lost Melee wielding a new familiar weapon, the target automatically rolls (Wits + Integrity). Successes on this roll negate the Charm's successes that have been applied to her. Mortals suffer a -1 external penalty to this roll.
   The roll for this Charm suffers a cumulative -1 external penalty for every use on a single target. These negated successes still damage the target.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Regalia Of Authority</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 159</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Compulsion</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Servitude</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit speaks as a godly commander, socially overwhelming every character who perceives it whose Essence score is not greater than the spirit's own. The mental influence the spirit exerts against such inferiors is unnatural. More importantly, everyone affected immediately gains a normal Intimacy toward worshiping the god, unless his Mental Defense Value is greater than its Temperance. While the Charm remains active, such weak minds even suffer from a Servitude Compulsion effect to honor and serve the god, which can only be resisted at the cost of one Willpower per action. Spending (spirit's Essence) temporary Willpower frees a target from the Compulsion, but not the Intimacy. Finally, the spirit's may substitute its Essence for its Appearance score for the duration of this Charm.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Stoke The Flame</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 159</reference>
        <cost>3m per dot of Magnitude</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2; Type:Supplemental</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>
        </type>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm adds (spirit's Temperance) automatic successes to a social Performance attack designed to provoke an emotion. If the roll is successful or the target is otherwise willing, the Charm induces an unnatural mental influence emotion; this counts as (spirit's Temperance) scenes building or eroding an intimacy defined by the spirit. Furthermore, everyone affected must act on the their induced feelings for the remainder of the scene, unless a target spends one Willpower point every action, in which case the Emotion effect only lasts till she's spent Willpower equal to the spirit's Temperance.
   Unresisting targets do as the spirit suggests; those who succumb recover all Willpower spent resisting this Charm (if any) and gain a pool of "Stoked Willpower" equal to the spirit's successes (maximum Temperance). Stoked Willpower is independent of a target's normal Willpower pool, can only be spent on actions relating to the spirit's suggestion and vanishes at the end of the scene.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Subtle Whisper</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Enchantments - Trickery Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits befuddle, awe and inspire.
   Enchantments override a target's essential belief structure. A high Mental Defense Value is a good defense, but Enchantments simply don't work on targets whose Essence scores are higher than the spirit's.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 159</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>A spirit supplementing an attempt at natural mental influence with Subtle Whisper won't obviously be the source of the influence. The spirit might roll to make a target calmer when it sees her enter its temple, for instance. Characters resisting the attempt with one Willpower may attempt to determine the source of this feeling; realizing that a social attack came from a divine source requires success on a (Perception + Occult) check with an external penalty of the spirit's Temperance.
   Subtle Whisper may be used by immaterial spirits against material targets.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Animating Management</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 160</reference>
        <cost>12m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit possesses an object, requiring Essence and Temperance scores greater than an artifact's level if the target is an artifact. (Possessed artifacts that require attunement to function still require that attunement). The spirit may then activate the object and use it as its designer intended. The spirit may use its own traits to accomplish things from within the object, but Attribute scores are limited to the spirit's Essence, and Abilities are limited to its Temperance. For instance, a spirit inhabiting a daiklave may swing it with ([lower of Dexterity or Essence] + [lower of Melee or Temperance]); the sword's bonuses would still count. A spirit in an Essence cannon could fire the cannon. Spirits possessing armor could walk the empty suits around. For the purposes of this Charm, "an object" needs to be a self-contained unit, but it may consist of multiple components, such as a suit of armor or a magitech artifact.
   By spending another 10 motes and one Willpower point, a spirit of Essence 3+ can imbue its possessed object with a certain level of flexibility. This might move the object in weird ways or allow it to be used it in a way it wasn't designed to be used.
   Spirits possessing objects can be recognized by anyone who can see the immaterial. Another spirit with domain over the inhabited object and higher Essence can eject the possessing spirit just by wishing to, but this takes a scene.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Commandeer</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 160</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Charm has two effects. If the spirit touches a host and a successful roll of the spirit's (Essence + Temperance) is made against an external penalty of a possessing spirit's ([Essence + Temperance] / 2), it may eject the current inhabitant. Second, if this Charm is used while another character is attempting to eject or exercise the spirit from its host, it may activate this Charm to add an external penalty of (spirit's Temperance) to any rolls to do so. Any character who is successfully rebuked through either effect of this Charm by a spirit with a higher Essence than her own loses a number of Willpower points, is knocked back a number of yards and is considered Inactive for a number of actions equal to the difference in Essence scores.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Hollow Out The Soul</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 160</reference>
        <cost>20m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Crippling</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One day or instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit erodes the soul of a creature the spirit's inhabiting. It attacks a part of its host's soul, usually a Virtue or Willpower, and its player rolls (Essence + Temperance), applying an external penalty of (the host's Essence). If the spirit scores more successes than the rating of the trait the spirit wishes to damage, that trait is reduced by one dot. If this power is used again on the same target within a week, successes from earlier in the week carry over; but once a dot has been lost, accumulated successes vanish.
   The traits of an Exalt or similarly fortified creature will return at a rate of one dot per week once the spirit stops hollowing her soul, but mortal traits don't recover without magical aid.
   If a spirit possesses at least four more dots of permanent Essence than the spirit's target, the spirit may also attack the host's permanent Essence, but must score (5 x normal) successes to damage that trait. Exalts are immune to this effect.
   If the motes powering this Charm are committed for a full day, the spirit works slowly. It may attempt to conceal its actions, represented by a (Manipulation + Temperance) roll, suffering a (host's [Perception + Occult] / 2) external penalty; but if the spirit is successful, the target is unaware of the attack even if one of her traits loses a dot.
   Hosts reduced to 0 Willpower can't contest Inhabitings.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Landscape Hide</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 161</reference>
        <cost>6m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit exists in an object or natural feature. While inhabiting it, the spirit senses only its host and what touches it, and cannot affect its host in any way. Thus tucked away, the spirit can't easily be analyzed; only its existence can be detected, and then only through the use of thaumaturgy or similar powers that examine objects spiritually. Measure the Wind, Essence sight and other such generic powers don't differentiate objects containing spirits using this Charm from those that don't.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Possession</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 161</reference>
        <cost>12m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit fills a gap in a mortal soul. While dematerialized, the spirit must "touch" the target and select one of her Virtues; if the spirit's Essence exceeds both the target's Essence and the selected Virtue, then roll the spirit's (Essence + Temperance). This roll suffers an external penalty of the target's (Essence + [higher of selected Virtue or Integrity]). If the spirit uses Possession while or immediately after the target takes an act on an action that forced him to override a Virtue of 3+ (see Exalted, p. 102), that Virtue counts as 2.
   If the roll is successful, the spirit may take control of the target's actions whenever it sees fit. The target loses all control. The spirit must use the host's Physical Attributes. The spirit may, but doesn't have to, use the host's voice and senses. Without using Charms, it can't perform physical actions that the host can't. The host retains her attunements, and if the spirit knows how, it may use the host's artifacts. Any physical properties of the host are the spirit's to command, but it can't draw on the host's Essence or use her Charms (Charms that were already active instantly end when the spirit floods into its target).
   The player of a host with a permanent Willpower score of 1 or higher can at any time make a (Willpower + Integrity) roll, adding (Essence) successes, in an attempt to regain control from the spirit. The spirit's player resists with a (Willpower + Temperance) roll, adding (Essence) successes. If the spirit wins, it retains control, and the host loses one Willpower point. If the host wins, he gains control for a number of actions equal to the successes scored in excess of the spirit's player's roll, and the spirit loses one Willpower point. If the host scores successes in excess of the spirit's successes equal to the spirit's Temperance, the spirit is ejected. Hosts may not regain Willpower while possessed.
   If a spirit uses Possession on a target reduced to zero permanent Willpower (most often through Hollow out the Soul, see p. 160), the Charm's duration becomes indefinite.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Ride</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Inhabitings - Possessed By The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Immaterial spirits can go places that material creatures can't, such as into people or objects.
   Inhabitings require a material host, such as a person, object or natural feature. People must be living. Objects must be at least whole enough to function. Natural features must be at least man-sized, but cannot usually exceed the size of a large tree. If a spirit's host becomes unusable - for instance, an elemental dematerializes, a person dies or an object is broken - the spirit is ejected over at least five ticks, during which time the spirit's Inactive. Ejection deals 10 dice of aggravated damage that can only be soaked internally, and probably not at all.
   Under normal circumstances, only one spirit may inhabit any potential target, by immaterially touching it and entering the same space that it occupies. Living creatures' souls don't count as possessing spirits for this purpose. Because most Essence 1 spirits can use the Charm Landscape Hide, it can be difficult for a spirit to find a place to inhabit that isn't the spirit's own domain.
   Inhabiting spirits are counted as immaterial for the purpose of determining what can affect them. They cannot move independently of their host without ending the Inhabiting. The external soak of the host does not stack with the external soak of the inhabiting spirit.
   Inhabitings can only be used while immaterial. Inhabiting spirits are considered material, except that they may continue to perform Inhabitings, and become immaterial if they leave their host.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 161</reference>
        <cost>18m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit enters a willing host. The result is often an uncomfortable amalgam of man and spirit vying for consciousness, thought and dominance, but sometimes, a true and beneficial union occurs. If either spirit or host boasts three or more dots of permanent Essence than the other, or they don't have similar positive Intimacies toward each other, the union will be incomplete. Otherwise, after an uninterrupted month of this Charm, the union becomes complete.
   In an incomplete union, the partner with the highest Essence dominates, and the gestalt entity has the dominant partner's traits. Only the dominant character may use her Charms, but gains the use of (spirit's Temperance) of the other character's Charms. These are chosen by the spirit when it begins its ride. The dominant character uses the formula that she'd normally use to compute her Essence pool, but if either character was an Exalt, all their motes become peripheral.
   In a complete union, the personalities mix, keeping no secrets from each other. A number of traits equal to the spirit's Temperance use the highest of their two scores - these are the traits with the largest difference between spirit and host, and are never Willpower or Essence The traits that don't use the higher of the two characters' scores are averaged and rounded up, including Willpower and Essence. Furthermore, the pair may use all their Charms and may even Combo them normally. The team uses the most advantageous of the two formulas for calculating their Essence pool, but if either of the characters was an Exalt, their motes are still all peripheral.
   No matter what, both characters retain their Virtues and can channel through either set as usual. Whenever the gestalt entity faces circumstances that challenge Virtues, each partner must check for Virtues influencing behavior separately. A gestalt with two Valor scores each at 4 would have to fail two subsequent Valor checks to stand down from a martial challenge.
   In the mists of prehistory, the patron gods of the Dragon Kings merged with the saurian race's heroes to become olchiliké, which means "Chosen" in High Holy Speech (this name was later appropriated by mortals and applied to the Exalted). Some gods near Rathess still possess Ride, but it's rare throughout the rest of Creation. The Immaculate Order especially considers this power blasphemy and acts against spirits known to use it.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Bread Of Weak Spirit</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Tantra - The Hunger Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits devour life with these Charms.
   How a spirit sustains itself matters. A spirit's form shifts to match the resonance of the Essence on which it subsists. The changes occur subtly over time, but mindful spirits can see them happening. Weak or easily manipulated spirits might show signs after a season, while stronger spirits remain unchanged for years, even centuries.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 162</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit consumes another willing (or Incapacitated) spirit, inflicting up to its Essence in aggravated levels of damage. For every such health level, the cannibalizing spirit converts one lethal health level of damage to bashing or recovers five motes.
   Instead of inflicting a level of aggravated damage to the target, a spirit can also drain one Willpower point or 10 motes. If the spirit cannibalizes a being of higher Essence, the spirit may also recover one Willpower point for every two health levels, but can't bring its own temporary Willpower higher than its Temperance.
   It's worth noting that, for the purposes of this Charm, Exaltations and the souls of living humans aren't spirits.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Fruit Of Living Essence</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Tantra - The Hunger Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits devour life with these Charms.
   How a spirit sustains itself matters. A spirit's form shifts to match the resonance of the Essence on which it subsists. The changes occur subtly over time, but mindful spirits can see them happening. Weak or easily manipulated spirits might show signs after a season, while stronger spirits remain unchanged for years, even centuries.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 162</reference>
        <cost>3m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit touches its target and its player rolls (Essence + Temperance), with an external penalty of (the target's Essence). If the target actively resists, she may add half her permanent Willpower to the external penalty; she can also consent, and thereby remove all penalties. Every success steals three motes of Essence, which go right to the spirit. If it scores three or more successes, it may steal one Willpower point instead of motes.
   A spirit stealing from a creature without an Essence pool still gains Essence or Willpower; the creature just pays the cost in other ways. She suffers a Crippling or Sickness effect that inflicts at least an internal penalty equal to the spirit's successes. This effect vanishes within a day from magically fortified creatures, but mortals must be treated normally. What sort of Crippling or Sickness effect the Charm inflicts depends on the spirit.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Meat Of Broken Flesh</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Tantra - The Hunger Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits devour life with these Charms.
   How a spirit sustains itself matters. A spirit's form shifts to match the resonance of the Essence on which it subsists. The changes occur subtly over time, but mindful spirits can see them happening. Weak or easily manipulated spirits might show signs after a season, while stronger spirits remain unchanged for years, even centuries.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 162</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit supplements an attack with this Charm, and if that attack deals any health levels of damage, the target loses (spirit's Essence) motes. If the attack inflicted lethal or aggravated damage, the spirit gains all those motes, but if it dealt bashing damage, the spirit only gains half those motes. Either way, the spirit can't gain more than (Essence + Temperance) motes from Meat of Broken Flesh during one normal action.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Spice Of Custodial Delectation</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Tantra - The Hunger Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits devour life with these Charms.
   How a spirit sustains itself matters. A spirit's form shifts to match the resonance of the Essence on which it subsists. The changes occur subtly over time, but mindful spirits can see them happening. Weak or easily manipulated spirits might show signs after a season, while stronger spirits remain unchanged for years, even centuries.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 162</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>During any scene in which the spirit's domain receives proper care, the spirit gains a mote of Essence. This can only be invoked if the care is performed by the spirit or by creatures within (its Essence x 100) yards, and those creatures' qualifications matter: A priest's ministrations net the spirit one mote for the scene. An occultist nets the spirit one mote per dot of Occult the occultist possesses. A group of otherwise unqualified individuals net the god one mote per dot of the group's Magnitude.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Wine Of Infinite Heartbreak</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Tantra - The Hunger Of The Gods (Temperance)</name>
            <description>Spirits devour life with these Charms.
   How a spirit sustains itself matters. A spirit's form shifts to match the resonance of the Essence on which it subsists. The changes occur subtly over time, but mindful spirits can see them happening. Weak or easily manipulated spirits might show signs after a season, while stronger spirits remain unchanged for years, even centuries.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 163</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Emotion</keyword>
        <keyword>Social</keyword>
        <keyword>Stackable</keyword>
        <duration>One week</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit flavors a mortal's Essence with divine power and drinks in the nectar of her joy. Repeated targets of this Charm become enthralled with the parasitic spirit, longing for the magical feeling of power and completion.
   This Charm supplements a social attack designed to build an Intimacy toward the spirit. If the attack is successful, the spirit invests a mote into the target for one week, and cannot retrieve the mote early. In exchange, it regains (target's Essence x 3) motes. (The spirit can stack the effect to receive [target's Essence x 3] motes for every mote still in the target, to a maximum of [Temperance] motes). If the target has an Intimacy toward the spirit, the spirit also regains one Willpower point.
   While this Charm is active, the target is counted as having at least as many scenes devoted to building an Intimacy toward the spirit as the number of motes invested in her. If the spirit has more motes in a target than her Conviction, she cannot even begin to break her commitment to the Intimacy while the Charm lasts.
   Each victim's hourly mote respiration rate is reduced by the number of motes invested in her. If this would bring her respiration rate to below 0 (as is always the case with mortals), she counts her permanent Willpower as one lower for each point below 0. Finally, if the target has an Intimacy to the spirit, and the spirit achieves a threshold on the original social attack greater than (target's Temperance), the target also suffers from an Emotion effect that forces her to spend two Willpower per day to avoid feeling so devoted to the spirit that she's practically its slave.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Blessed (Element) Body</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 163</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Elemental</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The blessing of an Elemental Dragon is upon the spirit, for harmful elemental energies become beautiful dancing dragons, butterflies or simple streams of power as they course into its hungry chakra, which glow in acceptance. The spirit has access to all of the benefits of Elemental Rejuvenation (see p. 170), and this Charm supersedes that power. Furthermore, if the spirit would be damaged by an effect of its chosen element, the spirit may spend two motes to perfectly and completely negate the damage from that effect. For every three dice or one health level of raw damage that the effect would have inflicted, the spirit instead heals one level of damage or regains one mote.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Destiny Sponsorship</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Indefinite</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit has reached an accord with destiny that shields the spirit from most casual troubles. This sacred contract imposes a an external penalty equal to the spirit's (Essence + Valor) to most rolls which could opposed by the spirit's Resistance, Integrity, or Dodge, even if the spirit is unaware of the effect. The spirit also gains soak equal to its (Essence + Valor) against most lethal or bashing damage. The only things that bypass this power are Essence-enhanced effects intended to affect the spirit specifically and the machinations of character with a Destiny (see Scroll of the Monk, pp. 151-152) greater than the spirit's ([Essence + Valor] / 2). This Charm has no effect during Calibration.
   The Destiny Sponsorship contract involves a number of taboos and restrictions equal to the spirit's Essence, which she must always observe. Any spirit who fails to observe these taboos loses the effects of this Charm and cannot reactivate it until Calibration.
   Any spirit requested to state the conditions of its Destiny Sponsorship in Old Realm must immediately and honestly do so, lest the spirit lose the benefits.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Divine Prerogative</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>None</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Solars</type>
            <name>Righteous Lion Defense</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Per Righteous Lion Defense (see Exalted, p. 199), save that the Intimacy must involve a material object, a creature weaker than the spirit, another spirit (to whom Creation believes the spirit owes fealty) or the spirit's domain.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Material Tribulation Divestment</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One action</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit briefly dematerializes, avoiding material consequences and removing material afflictions. The instant this Charm is used, the spirit dematerializes. On the tick the Charm is used, its action switches to Inactive. During this time, all effects not designed to affect immaterial being pass through it harmlessly. Ongoing Crippling, Poison and Sickness effects not specifically designed to affect immaterial spirits become heavy vestments, imbedded weapons and sucking leeches on the spirit's immaterial form. It automatically knows which hindrances relate to which effects and may remove a number of them equal to its Valor. Effects created through magic resist being cast off, and the spirit must score successes equal to the Essence rating of the effect on a roll of (Essence + Valor). Failure not only means that the spirit cannot remove the item, but also that the spirit has spent the rest of its action trying. Attempts to remove effects backed by an Essence score higher than the spirit's automatically fail. At the conclusion of this Charm, the spirit rematerializes in the same place that it was before.
   If the immaterial items created by this Charm are replaced on the spirit, then their effects resume.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Ox-Body Technique</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>-</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Permanent</type>
        <keyword>Stackable</keyword>
        <duration>Permanent</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit gains extra health levels (one -1 and one -2). This Charm may be purchased (spirit's Essence) times.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Sheathing The Material Form</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>1m per 1B/halfL</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>For every two motes spent, the spirit increases its lethal soak and hardness by 1 and bashing soak by 2. A spirit may spend no more than (Essence x Valor) motes on this Charm.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Symbol Of Invincible Authority</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Aegis - Shields Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits do what they can to stay immortal.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 164</reference>
        <cost>10m, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>A glowing rune symbolizing the spirit's domain appears surrounding it, announcing to all things its divine authority over its concept. The spirit becomes effectively immune to its domain. Poison, Sickness and Crippling effects originating from the spirit's domain all mean nothing. The spirit's even immune to such effects caused only in part by its domain, unless they're backed by an Essence greater than its Valor. Raw damage related to the spirit's domain is reduced to 0 before any added by Charms. If the spirit's domain has a social component, the spirit may create a temporary magical Intimacy involving its domain. Any mental influence opposing this Intimacy counts as an unacceptable order.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Claws Of The Angry Dragon</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 165</reference>
        <cost>3m+, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit removes powers such as those bestowed by the
    blessing Touch of Divinity (see p. 146). The spirit doesn't steal Essence or Willpower; the spirit simply drains it. This Charm can't unawaken a target's Essence. Touch of Divinity doesn't actually awaken Essence; the Charm simply grants its target power that helps her awaken on her own.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Dreaded Embrace Of Mundanity</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 165</reference>
        <cost>15m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>By interrupting the connection between the target and the source of her power, the spirit may negate the dice that a particular one of the target's Excellencies would add at a cost of one mote per die. The spirit can't negate more Excellency-added dice than its Essence, and the target can't spend more motes than she would normally be able to (i.e., the target's dice pool cap is reduced by every mote the spirit spends). The spirit may counteract an Excellency (Valor) times with a single invocation of this curse.
   Blocking power to an Exalted Essence is like smothering a fire by closing your fist around it, and deals to the spirit one die of armor-bypassing aggravated damage for every die the spirit attempts to negate.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Malediction</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 165</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target receives a one-die penalty to rolls related to a certain task (or all rolls, in the case of All-Encompassing Malediction).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Plague Of Menaces</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 165</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The target is marked as the spirit's enemy (though the sigil may only be visible to senses that penetrate the immaterial). All of the spirit's subordinates treat the mark as an order to harm the target. Some spirits resent this Charm, but they must still obey it. Non-subordinates who have reason to support the spirit's agenda, and any spirits looking for an excuse to make the target's life difficult or have fun at the target's expense may also participate in the curse.
   The Division of Endings has authority over five plagues: diseased rats, poisonous amphibians, hungry locusts, feral dogs and ichneumon. These creatures take great joy in harassing targets of this Charm and all those around him. Most spirits with this Charm know how to call down at least one of these menaces.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Scourge</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 166</reference>
        <cost>Varies, 1wp</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <crossRef>
            <type>Spirits</type>
            <name>Endowment</name>
        </crossRef>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Scorge functions as per Endowment (see p. 146), save that this Charm removes positive traits, bestows negative traits or removes the effects of a Charm. For traits, the cost to remove them is identical to the cost to Endow them. For physical alterations, all positive effects are switched with their equivalent negative effects. The spirit may only remove the use or effects of a Charm that the spirit can itself use. If the spirit removes the effects of a Charm, those effects are negated for as long as the Charm would last if the spirit used the Charm upon the target. However, spirits Scourge targets of traits they don't possess.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Taste Of Mortality</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 166</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <keyword>Touch</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>This Curse removes such abilities as those bestowed by the blessing Touch of Eternity (see p. 147), and can make targets without those abilities considerably weaker.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Touch Of Saturn</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Curses - Wrath Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits curse their nemeses and battle foes, of course, but most often use these Charms to show displeasure with a mistaken follower.
   A cursing spirit must normally be within (Essence x 100) yards of Essence 1 targets, but may be further away if it has an arcane link. Essence 2+ targets must be within (Essence) yards. Some spirits take Supplemental versions of Curses that affect their natural attacks or other offensive actions.
       Like Blessings, Curses do not require a roll to enact. However, a spirit attempting to curse a character with a higher Essence score than its own increases the minimum Essence of the Charm by the difference between the characters' Essence score.
   Furthermore, targets who defy the spirit may spend one Willpower to attempt to shrug off the effect, but may attempt this only once for each effect. This spiritual resistance requires only a successful Essence roll, but the roll suffers a -1 external penalty for every point the spirit's Essence exceeds the target's. A particular curse may only be attempted once per scene per target.
   Curses affecting Essence 1 creatures continue to affect them for the duration of the Charm or until the spirit calls the effect off, even if the spirit releases the committed Essence. However, they only affect Essence 2+ creatures while the spirit keeps the necessary motes committed.
   Some spirits may issue Curses that deactivate under certain conditions.
   Different Curses with similar effects don't stack.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 166</reference>
        <cost>3m+, 1wp+</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Shaping</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>For every three motes the spirit spends, its target suffers one lethal health level of damage or two bashing health levels of damage. Spirits of Essence 4+ can change the damage from lethal to aggravated by adding one Willpower point per level. The spirit may spend no more than ([lower of Essence or Valor] x 3) motes on this Charm.
   The Touch of Saturn can inflict Crippling, Poison or Sickness effects. To determine the mote cost, each counts as a number of lethal health levels equal to a Poison's Toxicity, a Sickness's Untreated Morbidity or a Crippling effect's relative seriousness, as decided by the Storyteller on a scale of 1 to 5. Unusually powerful effects may count as up to 10 and are considered supernatural.
   Aggravated damage and supernatural Crippling, Poison or Sickness effects definitely vanish when this Charm's duration expires; other effects might not.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Bane Weapon</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 166</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Attacks supplemented by this Charm do aggravated damage. If the spirit's attack is useful against objects, it instead ignores the object's soak and Hardness. The limited nature of this Charm deserves special mention, as aggravated damage is particularly dangerous. There is no All-Encompassing Bane Weapon Charm; every spirit with Bane Weapon can inflict aggravated damage only upon a narrow range of creatures. For example, the demon Octavian (see Exalted, p. 309) may deal aggravated damage to earth elementals. Groups such as "all elementals" and "all mortals" are too broad for this Charm to encompass, though "all redheads", "all djala" or even "all men" would be possible. This Charm cannot distinguish between the Exalted and the unExalted, so no spirit has a Bane Weapon Charm that deals damage to all Exalted in general, all Solars, all Dragon-Blooded or the like. Generally speaking, this Charm is not used to represent increased competence against a particular opposed group; instead, this Charm is the manifestation of a grudge or vendetta that lies orthogonal to the spirit's assigned purpose.
   If the spirit's attack is useful against objects, attacks supplemented by this Charm instead ignore the object's soak and hardness.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Essence Bite</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 166</reference>
        <cost>Varies</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Basic</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit does damage to every creature that strikes the spirit, touches it or is struck by it. The Charm can deal bashing damage at a cost of one mote per die, lethal damage for two motes per die or aggravated damage for four motes per die. Lethal damage requires the spirit to have at least two Essence. Aggravated damage requires four Essence. No more than ([Essence x 2] + Valor) motes may be spent per invocation.
   A more potent effect - inflicting health levels rather than dice, and bypassing armor - would raise the cost by one mote per health level and the Charm's minimum Essence by 1. If the damage takes the form of an element, this Charm carries the Elemental keyword.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Paralyze</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 167</reference>
        <cost>6m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <keyword>Variable</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit converts an attack's damage into a Crippling effect, a Poison effect, a Sickness effect, a wound penalty, a Shaping effect or an unnatural mental influence (pick one). Until the spirit's next action, all the target's non-reflexive dice pools are reduced by (spirit's Essence), or one of her traits is reduced by (spirit's Essence/2). For every three dots of (Essence + Valor) the spirit possesses, it may include an additional reason for the effect in the attack: for instance, a spirit with 6 (Essence + Valor) might inflict paralysis that's both a Sickness and a Poison effect.
   A target immune to all the associated keywords, or with an Essence higher than the spirit's, is immune to its version of Paralyze. Other targets resist Paralyze with a successful (Stamina + Resistance) roll, with an external penalty of the spirit's Valor.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shatter</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 167</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>4</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Extra Action</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit unleashes a cacophonic shout, a crushing wave of energy or some other all-encompassing attack on the area around it. The blast affects all creatures and/or objects within (Essence x 10) yards, and is either unblockable or undodgable. Whichever mode of defense works requires a Defense Value equal to the spirit's (Valor + Any Attribute) to avoid. Damage from the attack is equal to the spirit's (Essence + Valor + Attribute). This damage is usually bashing, but spirits of Essence 5+ may spend an additional five motes and one Willpower to convert the damage to piercing bashing or lethal damage. Shatter is a natural attack. If the spirit uses other Charms to supplement Shatter, count it as a number of attacks equal to the spirit's ([Essence + Valor + Attribute] / 2).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Shattered Adamant Attack</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 168</reference>
        <cost>10m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>5</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Attacks supplemented by this Charm affect the material world. Subtract 5 from the spirit's effective Essence when enhancing the attack - the spirit cannot invoke other Charms that require a minimum Essence higher than the modified figure, and those Charms use the modified figure to calculate their effects.
   Unlike other Edges, Shattered Adamant Attack can obviously be used while immaterial; the attack itself becomes material before it begins, though, which might allow the target a roll to notice it. This also means other Edges can enhance it. If a spirit invokes this Charm more than (Valor) times in one scene, every additional use inflicts an unsoakable aggravated health level upon the spirit as its substance is lost in the rapid transition to materiality and back.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Spirit-Cutting</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 168</reference>
        <cost>2m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>Attacks supplemented by this Charm affect the immaterial.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Words Of Power</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Edges - Strikes Of The Gods (Valor)</name>
            <description>Spirits may not often interfere with Creation, but when they must fight, they're fearsome foes even of the Exalted.
   Unless otherwise stated, Supplemental Edges affect only a spirit's natural attacks and those made with its divine panoply (see p. 169).
   Edges can only be performed while material.</description>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 4 - Roll of Glorious Divinity I, page 168</reference>
        <cost>5m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>3</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-OK</keyword>
        <keyword>Obvious</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit rolls (Manipulation + Valor) to use its words as a physical attack against any creature it could socially attack. This attack does a base bashing damage of (Valor) in health levels; successes add damage dice, as normal; the whole can only be soaked naturally. For every health level of damage the target suffers, she incurs a -1 internal penalty to all actions or a -2 internal penalty to actions with a specific Ability for (spirit's Essence x 3) ticks.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Essence Bite</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 146</reference>
        <cost>3m (which can be provided by the AI, the pilot or any reserves within the warstrider)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Valor</name>
            <value>3</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 5)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>When used by an AI, this Charm can add to the damage the pilot can inflict on a standard Martial Arts attack, charging the warstrider's hands with damaging Essence. During the scene in which the Charm is active, roll the AI's (Valor + Essence) every time the pilot successfully strikes a target in hand-to-hand combat. Each success adds one die to the pilot's damage pool, and all that damage is lethal.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Tracking</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 146</reference>
        <cost>5m (which can be provided by the AI, the pilot or any reserves within the warstrider)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Compassion</name>
            <value>2</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 6)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The spirit can track someone or something with a successful (Perception + Compassion) check. The difficulty of the check is equal to the Essence of the creature being tracked (or 1 in the case of a quarry without an Essence trait), modified by any supernatural evasive techniques the quarry can bring to bear.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Camouflage</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 146</reference>
        <cost>10m (which must come exclusively from the AI)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Temperance</name>
            <value>3</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 6)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The AI can camouflage the warstrider's form to blend in with the ambient environment. Roll (Wits + Temperance). Successes on the roll are added to the successes from any other Stealth-related roll made by the pilot's player. The effects of this Charm can stack with any Charm a pilot is capable of using, as well as the effects of any ancillary cloaking systems (see pp. 155-156).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Donning Spiritual Armor</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 146</reference>
        <cost>5m (which must come from the AI)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Temperance</name>
            <value>2</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Simple (Speed 6)</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>One scene</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The AI can augment the incredible soak of the warstrider's exoskeleton even further. When the AI spends the requisite Essence, the bashing and lethal soak of the warstrider increased by (the AI's Temperance + Essence). Additionally, the warstrider and its pilot are protected from all environmental dangers such as excessive heat and cold, as if the pilot had used the Hardship-Surviving Mendicant Spirit Charm (see Exalted, p. 210).</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Uncanny Prowess</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 146</reference>
        <cost>2m (which may come from the AI or the warstrider's reserves, but not the pilot)</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Valor</name>
            <value>2</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>1</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Reflexive</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>Special</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>The AI can add dice equal to its Valor to any single Dexterity roll made by the pilot in the course of operating the warstrider. This roll can be anything from a single attack to an extended roll to tear down a fortified wall. When applied to extended rolls, the Charm adds dice to each roll. These dice, however, can be added to only a single endeavor (which must involve some action undertaken by the warstrider), and the Charm cannot be recast until the first task has been completed or abandoned.</description>
    </charms>
    <charms>
        <name>Spirit-Cutting</name>
        <creator>White Wolf</creator>
        <category>
            <name>Warstrider AI Charms</name>
        </category>
        <reference>Book of Sorcery, vol. 1 - Wonders of the Lost Age, page 147</reference>
        <cost>1m</cost>
        <skill>
            <name>Valor</name>
            <value>3</value>
        </skill>
        <skill>
            <name>Essence</name>
            <value>2</value>
            <primary>true</primary>
        </skill>
        <type>Supplemental</type>
        <keyword>Combo-Ok</keyword>
        <duration>Instant</duration>
        <prerequest>
            <name>None</name>
        </prerequest>
        <description>When this Charm is activated, the warstrider can launch a single attack against an unmanifested spirit.</description>
    </charms>
</body>